<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I-Need-Self-Curated-News-For-The-Irish-General-Election-Ge11s on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/i-need-self-curated-news-for-the-irish-general-election-ge11.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in I-Need-Self-Curated-News-For-The-Irish-General-Election-Ge11s on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 19:16:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/i-need-self-curated-news-for-the-irish-general-election-ge11.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I need self-curated news for the Irish General Election #ge11</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/i-need-self-curated-news-for-the-irish-general-election-ge11/i-need-self-curated-news-for-the-irish-general-election-ge11.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2011 19:16:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/i-need-self-curated-news-for-the-irish-general-election-ge11/i-need-self-curated-news-for-the-irish-general-election-ge11.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;I need self-curated news for the Irish General Election #ge11&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#39;m lashing together a quick &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/conoro/general-election-2011-10&#34;&gt;General Election list&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter for my Dad to follow. He&amp;#39;s not on Twitter but he loves politics and I think he&amp;#39;d get a kick out of it. I started with some of the obvious MSM accounts and then some people&lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;I know who are interested in politics. Then I looked at some of their lists. I&amp;#39;ve put a simple one together that I think he&amp;#39;ll like. It&amp;#39;s nowhere near finished yet but it&amp;#39;s a start. &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Except of course it has a huge problem. It shows everything those people are tweeting. Every inanity, every irrelevant detail. What I need is the intersection of that list and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/search?q=%23ge11&#34;&gt;#ge11 hashtag&lt;/a&gt;. There is no way I wouldrecommendhe follows the hashtag if he wants to keep his sanity. 50,000 people all bitching about the same thing at the same time is not interesting to anyone.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;So does such a webapp or desktop app exist? If not, why not? It&amp;#39;s another Twitter app I would pay for.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;And if it could pull in Wall updates from Facebook Pages of politicians etc, that would be worth even more!&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Am I the only one on Twitter who needs these kind of tools (like all my Filter requests) or is the perception that the money lies elsewhere?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>