<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sugru-Old-Mondeo-Yays on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/sugru-old-mondeo-yay.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sugru-Old-Mondeo-Yays on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 17:17:59 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/sugru-old-mondeo-yay.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Sugru &#43; Old Mondeo = Yay</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/sugru-old-mondeo-yay/sugru-old-mondeo-yay.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2012 17:17:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/sugru-old-mondeo-yay/sugru-old-mondeo-yay.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Sugru + Old Mondeo = Yay&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ancient old Ford Mondeo (2001) is still going strong. In some ways I hate it for doing so. It&amp;rsquo;s an appliance and I don&amp;rsquo;t like appliances, I like things with character. Prior to it I only bought Citroens (BX, AX, Xantia) and I loved them dearly. But they were unreliable piles of junk assembled by drunks. Then, once we had kids, an appliance became necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;New&amp;rdquo; Mondeo was the second car in the renaissance of Ford. The first was the Focus in 1999. My wife had a Focus and it was as close to perfect a car as you could get. Interesting shapes inside and out, totally reliable and not a generic over-priced BMW. Her sister drove it for a few years after her and loved it too. The Mondeo kept the reliability of the Focus but was dead boring to look at, inside and out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 11 years, the only problems it has had are a badly designed handbrake and grab handles which pop out of the ceiling. It also loses the gas in the aircon too quickly and it needed a suspension joint replaced a few years ago. It gets one service a year across the road for 100+ and that&amp;rsquo;s it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;120,000 miles later and it bombs up and down the M7/M8 like a new car.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in all this time, one thing has bugged me every day. The dashboard has a stippled effect which is a magnet for dust but is also impossible to attach anything too. Particularly phone holders. So I&amp;rsquo;ve always had to attach them to the windscreen. The problem there is that the angle of the screen is so severe, it is always awkward, in landscape-mode, far away and murdered by glare. In France, on holidays in July, the HTC Sensation overheated so badly using Google Maps Navigation that a 2 Amp charger couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep the battery charged!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then yesterday, 11 years later, I had a brainwave. Sugru:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/-91rGSM_mHJQ/UEtKoUAtmuI/AAAAAAAAiy8/LZsyQHZGFr8/s800/IMG_20120908_143516.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ye know what? It flippin works!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s to another 120,000 miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>