<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How-The-Hell-Did-I-Miss-The-Upcoming-Shutdown-Of-Feedburner-Another-Lesson-In-Lock-Ins on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/how-the-hell-did-i-miss-the-upcoming-shutdown-of-feedburner-another-lesson-in-lock-in/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How-The-Hell-Did-I-Miss-The-Upcoming-Shutdown-Of-Feedburner-Another-Lesson-In-Lock-Ins on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 19:09:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/how-the-hell-did-i-miss-the-upcoming-shutdown-of-feedburner-another-lesson-in-lock-in/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>How the hell did I miss the upcoming shutdown of FeedBurner? Another lesson in lock-in.</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/how-the-hell-did-i-miss-the-upcoming-shutdown-of-feedburner-another-lesson-in-lock-in/how-the-hell-did-i-miss-the-upcoming-shutdown-of-feedburner-another-lesson-in-lock-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2012 19:09:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/how-the-hell-did-i-miss-the-upcoming-shutdown-of-feedburner-another-lesson-in-lock-in/how-the-hell-did-i-miss-the-upcoming-shutdown-of-feedburner-another-lesson-in-lock-in/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;How the hell did I miss the upcoming shutdown of FeedBurner? Another lesson in lock-in.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How the hell did I miss the fact that Google is shutting down FeedBurner in October?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always remember Dave Winer &lt;a href=&#34;http://scripting.com/stories/2007/07/21/whyFeedburnerIsTrouble.html&#34;&gt;warning all us bloggers&lt;/a&gt; back in 2007 that we were nuts to insert a single company between us and our readers.Most of us thought he was being a crank. It turns out he was right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My big worry is that we will all lose all of our Blog Subscribers. In my case, built up over 11 years. I&amp;rsquo;ll be optimistic and assume some sort of skeleton FeedBurner service will exist which will 301 re-direct all the feeds to the original sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Great round-up piece on the problem by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nevillehobson.com/2012/09/09/prepare-for-goodbye-feedburner-in-october-2012/&#34;&gt;Neville Hobson&lt;/a&gt;. Two solutions &lt;a href=&#34;http://threads.scripting.com/8312ByDw/theFutureOfFeedburner&#34;&gt;offered by Dave&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many times are we going to fall for this before we learn? We see a service that offers us some really nice benefits for free (FeedBurner, Facebook , Twitter, etc etc). Then we choose to ignore what will happen if they go away or change the rules or just break. We decide lock-in is a fair swap for free. Then they go away or change the rules or just break. And we&amp;rsquo;re left high and dry, swearing never again. Until the next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily I&amp;rsquo;ve only got two blogs left using FeedBurner. Unluckily they are the two most trafficked. I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can do the CNAME transition before D-Day and report back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: Someone left a comment on Google+ saying that it is just specific APIs that are getting shutdown, not the overall service. If I can confirm that, I&amp;rsquo;ll report back. Meanwhile, I&amp;rsquo;m still going to make the CNAME move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>