<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patriot-Pbo-Core-Is-A-Very-Nice-Cheap-Media-Player-Devices on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/patriot-pbo-core-is-a-very-nice-cheap-media-player-device.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patriot-Pbo-Core-Is-A-Very-Nice-Cheap-Media-Player-Devices on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 14:20:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/patriot-pbo-core-is-a-very-nice-cheap-media-player-device.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Patriot PBO Core is a very nice cheap Media Player device</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/patriot-pbo-core-is-a-very-nice-cheap-media-player-device/patriot-pbo-core-is-a-very-nice-cheap-media-player-device.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 14:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/patriot-pbo-core-is-a-very-nice-cheap-media-player-device/patriot-pbo-core-is-a-very-nice-cheap-media-player-device.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Patriot PBO Core is a very nice cheap Media Player device&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written at length about our media setup at home. The main box remains a low-end PC with a decent graphics card and HDMI-out. It mainly runs &lt;a href=&#34;http://xbmc.org/&#34;&gt;XBMC&lt;/a&gt;but we switch over to Windows Media Centre for playing/recording satellite/terrestial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have had two old XBOXes running XBMC for years and they are awesome. Their only drawback is that they don&amp;rsquo;t have enough welly to play h.264 so no MP4s, MKVs, 720p or 1080p.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year I got a tiny media playing box called the HDVP-2. I put a 500GB harddisk inside it and it plays everything. It has HDMI, Composite, LAN, USB and an option for WIFI. It&amp;rsquo;s our travel media box and is perfect for hotels or visiting parents and in-laws. However, it has four problems:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;It can&amp;rsquo;t browse networks shares over SMB, it only does UPNP. We have all media centralised and shared out over SMB. I use TVersity for UPNP sharing but I just hate the whole UPNP approach.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;It loses audio-video sync on many AVIs very quickly and doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a manual audio-offset like XBMC&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t spin down the internal harddisk so you have to unplug it except when playing videos&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They aren&amp;rsquo;t making it any more so there will be no bug-fixes or updates and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find any Open Source software that runs on it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Then two weeks ago, one of the XBOXes died, the one we have setup for the treadmill. I refused to use the HDVP-2 due to the AV sync problem and wondered what the best approach might be. I was tempted by one of those dirt-cheap ROKU boxes and discovered they can play local media using a Private Channel trick, in addition to Netflix, but I figured it&amp;rsquo;d be as fiddly as UPNP on the HDVP-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then Irememberedthe &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Patriot-PCMPBO25-Office-Definition-Player/dp/B002Q4U9PY/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1329660253&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;Patriot PBO Core&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;d discussed with &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/swhelband&#34;&gt;@swhelband&lt;/a&gt; last year. He had bought one and tweeted very positively about it. A quick check revealed it was still for sale on amazon.co.uk for 60. I made sure it had SMB support and then happily ordered. It&amp;rsquo;s a very similar spec to the HDVP-2 but executed far better, so you get:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Very high quality metal case which can take an internal 2.5&amp;rdquo; hard-disk if you want&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;HDMI-out&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Composite-out&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Up to 1080p&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Plays every format you can throw at it&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;LAN with playing of both SMB and UPNP sources&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;USB&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Remote control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patriotmemory.com/products/detailp.jsp?prodline=6&amp;amp;catid=69&amp;amp;prodgroupid=159&amp;amp;id=895&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-large wp-image-592&#34; title=&#34;PBO_Core_IsoRight&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/PBO_Core_IsoRight-1024x1024.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;584&#34; height=&#34;584&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve have it for over a week now and the experience has been mixed. The core functionality is rock solid and I&amp;rsquo;m sure it works perfectly as a local media player. The main issues we&amp;rsquo;ve had have been around network playing. The default firmware has some features which become really annoying, such as:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Insists on checking size etc of every file in a directory as you scroll through. Unbearably slow when doing this over the network.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pops-up network access speed as you scroll through files. As if you care!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an &amp;ldquo;already watched&amp;rdquo; indicator which is a bit of a pain&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Won&amp;rsquo;t let you add top-level shortcuts to specific directories on specific networked machines so you can jump quickly to your stuff after power-on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Luckily the PBO Core is using a reference design (I assume from Realtek) and there are other boxes out there with the same hardware but improved software. I finally found one that avoids all thenetworkproblems &lt;a href=&#34;http://patriot-box-office.wikidot.com/pbo-alternative-custom-firmwares&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (I used the v3.2 Mod from Shizzl of the MedeBO firmware). Upgrading is doddle and you just pop the file onto a USB stick and select &amp;ldquo;System Update&amp;rdquo; on the PBO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m now a very happy bunny and have exactly what I need. Sure it&amp;rsquo;s nowhere near as slick as XBMC but for 60 I&amp;rsquo;m not going to complain too much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it shares one downside with the HDVP-2. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much end-of-lifed and hasn&amp;rsquo;t had a software update since early in 2011. I read recently that Patriot is releasing a much higher-spec Android-based device soon. But if the PBO Core meets your needsthen the lack of updates is not a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Android devices, Richard Hearne spotted &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iboum.com/pr/him900a.php&#34;&gt;this awesome looking piece of kit&lt;/a&gt;. It is more than double the price of the PBO but the feature list is damned impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also finally gave in and replaced the 10 year old Philips portable 14&amp;rdquo; TV as the display and got a really nice &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/LG-IPS225V-Advanced-Performance-Widescreen/dp/B0060LCBRI/ref=sr_1_1?s=computers&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1329660920&amp;amp;sr=1-1&#34;&gt;LG 22&amp;rdquo; IPS, LED 1080p&lt;/a&gt; display from Amazon for 110 last week too. The picture quality with this combo is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course if you have an Android phone like a HTC Sensation, you could just use the MHL HDMI-out to achive most of the above. I bet one of the Bluetooth remotes or headset controls would do the trick for selecting the movies etc. I must try mine in a network streaming configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh I&amp;rsquo;ll also blog shortly about using a US VPN and PlayOn to deliver Netflix over UPNP to the PBO Core. To be honest it was so much hassle you should just buy a Roku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>