<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alleluia-How-To-Specify-Which-Google-Account-In-The-Urls on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/alleluia-how-to-specify-which-google-account-in-the-url.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alleluia-How-To-Specify-Which-Google-Account-In-The-Urls on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 18:05:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/alleluia-how-to-specify-which-google-account-in-the-url.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Alleluia - How to specify which Google Account in the URL</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/alleluia-how-to-specify-which-google-account-in-the-url/alleluia-how-to-specify-which-google-account-in-the-url.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 May 2012 18:05:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/alleluia-how-to-specify-which-google-account-in-the-url/alleluia-how-to-specify-which-google-account-in-the-url.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Alleluia - How to specify which Google Account in the URL&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been driven demented by Google&amp;rsquo;s multi-login feature since it launched. Every damned tool of theirs seems to do it differently. The good ones let you flick seamlessly between accounts (Google+). The awful ones won&amp;rsquo;t let you select an alternative (yes you Picasa Web) and if you logout, you logout of everything. And of course, they always default to the one you don&amp;rsquo;t want (hellooo Google Reader).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a brainwave a few minutes ago - what if there was a way of specifying which account you want to use in the URL when accessing a Google application? And it turns out, praise jebus, there is. All you have to do is tack on ?authuser=N to the URL (or &amp;amp;authuser=N if there is already a parameter on the URL) where N=0 for the default account (i.e. the one you logged in with first), N=1 is the next account you logged in with, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now, rather than clicking a general bookmark for Google Reader which always goes to my unused loudervoice.com Reader account and then I have to switch, I can set the bookmark to &lt;a href=&#34;http://google.com/reader?authuser=1&#34;&gt;http://google.com/reader?authuser=1&lt;/a&gt; and go there directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for Picasa. Why Google, why?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One less thing to bug the crap out of me each day :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>