<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My-Next-Radio-Aint-A-Radios on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-next-radio-aint-a-radio.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in My-Next-Radio-Aint-A-Radios on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 15:20:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/my-next-radio-aint-a-radio.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Next Radio ain&#39;t a Radio</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-next-radio-aint-a-radio/my-next-radio-aint-a-radio.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2011 15:20:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/my-next-radio-aint-a-radio/my-next-radio-aint-a-radio.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;My Next Radio ain&amp;rsquo;t a Radio&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a bit of messing this week on &lt;a href=&#34;http://Turntable.fm&#34;&gt;Turntable.fm&lt;/a&gt; followed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://music.google.com&#34;&gt;Google Music&lt;/a&gt; on my phone and I&amp;#39;ve been doing some mulling.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Google Music has been uploading my music collection to the cloud for a week. Probably another week to go. The genius bit is that the new music player on Android then shows all of your music. If a song is not on your phone and you try to play it, it&amp;#39;ll start streaming it. You choose if you only want to do that on Wifi or 3G too.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;So this morning I drove up to collect Oisn from soccer and, as usual, had my HTC Desire paired by Bluetooth to my Lidl car stereo. Then I picked a Lou Reed song that wasn&amp;#39;t on the phone and Google Music streamed it perfectly over 3G. Very impressed. Obviously will be rubbish in rural West Cork with the poor mobile coverage and I need to watch my data usage. But as a concept I love it.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Then you have Turntable.fm. A series of &amp;quot;rooms&amp;quot; dedicated to different types of music with a bunch of DJ slots available in each one. You can grab a slot and upload your music into your queue. The system then round-robin plays each DJs songs and those listening in the room can vote it up or down. Enough &amp;quot;Lames&amp;quot; and your song gets skipped. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/walter&#34;&gt;@walter&lt;/a&gt; described it as crack and he is 100% right. It is as close to a perfect game-play driven web-app as you can get. I&amp;#39;ve been in and out to the 80s rooms non-stop for days.I think my DJ name will be Transit van Driver.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;#39;ve never been much of a radio person. I&amp;#39;ll take wall-to-wall music any day over some fools prattling-on or god-awful phone-ins. The only talk radio I ever liked was Howard Stern in SV in 1996. And that was just for laughs. But of course the problem with music radio is the lowest common denominator playlists. So I guess most of us end up listening to our own music on our own phones/ipods. But then that leads to stagnation of tastes as you are not exposed to new stuff.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Google thinks (as always) the answer is an algorithm. They have Instant Mix in Google Music. &amp;quot;Here are more songs like the one you arelisteningto&amp;quot;. Yawn, &lt;a href=&#34;http://last.fm&#34;&gt;last.fm&lt;/a&gt; sorted that out years ago.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Then Gordon Murray (&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/murrion&#34;&gt;@murrion&lt;/a&gt;) nailed it &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/murrion/status/79517724014944257&#34;&gt;Wonder if turntable.fm could stream to it&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Imagine the music you listen to in your car is what a bunch of different people in specific rooms on &lt;a href=&#34;http://turntable.fm&#34;&gt;turntable.fm&lt;/a&gt; are playing, streamed to your phone over 3G and then to your dumb head-unit? Bluetooth based thumbs-up/thumbs-down and Room-Switcher for changing songs.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Jam in some ads or a subscription service and I&amp;#39;ve got My Next Radio.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>