<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Save-A-Packet-On-O2-Mobile-Broadband-Cancel-And-Re-Subscribes on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/save-a-packet-on-o2-mobile-broadband-cancel-and-re-subscribe.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Save-A-Packet-On-O2-Mobile-Broadband-Cancel-And-Re-Subscribes on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 09:16:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/save-a-packet-on-o2-mobile-broadband-cancel-and-re-subscribe.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Save a packet on O2 Mobile broadband. Cancel and re-subscribe</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/save-a-packet-on-o2-mobile-broadband-cancel-and-re-subscribe/save-a-packet-on-o2-mobile-broadband-cancel-and-re-subscribe.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2010 09:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/save-a-packet-on-o2-mobile-broadband-cancel-and-re-subscribe/save-a-packet-on-o2-mobile-broadband-cancel-and-re-subscribe.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Save a packet on O2 Mobile broadband. Cancel and re-subscribe&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve had O2 mobile broadband for something like 2 years. I haven&amp;#39;t used it much at all in the past few months and cancelled it a few weeks back. It was costing 30 p.m. for 10GB. &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;However the ongoing problems with Eircom DSL &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;single&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;night&lt;/em&gt; from 7pm to midnight has been driving me insane. Throughput drops to almost 0bps. The feedback I see on Twitter is that I&amp;#39;m not the only one and Cork seems to be particularly bad.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;So I finally setup the big assed external antenna connected to a Huawei E176 dongle and all seemed ok on that front as a backup. But Vodafone mobile broadband in Bandon is brutal due to really minuscule backhaul.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Yesterday I trotted off down to the O2 Shop in Bandon to sign up again. Now I&amp;#39;m getiing 15GB a month for 16.99 (normally 19.90). So my top Monday money saving tip - check your O2 bill. if you are giving them 30 a month for your dongle, cancel it.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Quick update on the external antenna. Yes it works in the attic, yes I get HSDPA but the throughput is very poor. So I&amp;#39;m going to have to bite the bullet and mount it outside somewhere where previous tests showed good throughput.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Second quick update - the E176 works perfectly plugged into my Billion Router.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>