<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The-Importance-Of-Interfaces on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-importance-of-interfaces/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The-Importance-Of-Interfaces on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 07:58:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/the-importance-of-interfaces/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Interfaces</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-importance-of-interfaces/the-importance-of-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 07:58:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/the-importance-of-interfaces/the-importance-of-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;The Importance of Interfaces&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve recently been thinking about how interfaces and standards are so important.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One challenge we have as a family with a huge number of kids is playing media when we visit various grandparents or in-laws. During the winter this is even more important. There are only so many DS games, episodes of iCarly or &lt;a href=&#34;http://y8.com&#34;&gt;y8.com&lt;/a&gt; games they will play. The same is true when I&amp;#39;m travelling and I want to chill out with a movie in a hotel and not be gouged.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the past year I&amp;#39;ve tried to do this with a laptop and VGA to Scart adapter. The picture quality is pretty awful but it does work.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Something like the new Apple TV initially looked interesting due to its small size. Then I saw the interface specs. No composite out , streaming only, no usb port, no sdcard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So forget that. I then looked at some of the cheap media players on Deal Extreme. They didn&amp;#39;t look too bad but reviews were patchy. Then I heard about the Nationite HDVP-2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://mp4nation.net/catalog/index.php?main_page=product_info&amp;amp;cPath=60&amp;amp;products_id=386&#34;&gt;http://mp4nation.net/catalog/index.php?main_page=product_info&amp;amp;cPath=60&amp;amp;products_id=386&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wow.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;1080p playback, composite/yuv/hdmi out, LAN, can take internal HDD, USB port, Sdcard slot, optional WiFi, streams from across network or uses local media, remote control, small size. And the real killer? $79!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve used it a bunch of times recently and it just totally rocks.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The best example of why a product like this, which only uses industry standard interfaces, is so useful, happened last weekend. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My sister wanted to show her daughter&amp;#39;s school play which was on their very cool JVC HDCam. Unfortunately the JVC uses some idiotic proprietary connector for TV-Out and she had forgotten the cable so my usual bag of wires was no use. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We were about to shrug and give up when I suddenly thought &amp;quot;wait a sec, what does it use for storage? &amp;quot;. Aha, Sdcard! I popped the card out, stuck it in the side of the HDVP-2 and voila, my niece on the old CRT TV.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;#39;s usb for charging , sdcards, audio jacks, rca jacks, sims, Bluetooth or cigarette lighters, standards and interfaces make your life easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>