<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My-368-Days-Of-Posterous-The-Stats on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-368-days-of-posterous-the-stats.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in My-368-Days-Of-Posterous-The-Stats on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 12:27:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/my-368-days-of-posterous-the-stats.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My 368 Days of Posterous - The Stats</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-368-days-of-posterous-the-stats/my-368-days-of-posterous-the-stats.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2011 12:27:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/my-368-days-of-posterous-the-stats/my-368-days-of-posterous-the-stats.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;My 368 Days of Posterous - The Stats&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hard to believe it&amp;rsquo;s been a full year since I started on Posterous. The idea behind it was simple - I was scatter-gunning techie posts across several blogs and they just didn&amp;rsquo;t belong there mixed in with foodie stuff and business. I wanted somewhere I could completely geek-out but with zero effort. Over the year I think most posts have taken 5 minutes to write and the bulk of them were sent by email when I was killing some time or on a lazy Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the headline stats since Feb 3rd 2010 according to Posterous:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;285 Posts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25 Posterous Subscribers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;143,147 views&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we know, Posterous just randomly invents view numbers so take that last one with a big pinch of salt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the Posterous numbers were right then my initial posts have had 200-300 views over the year and my more recent ones had 3000-4000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have to say I&amp;rsquo;m not tempted to move from Posterous despite the lock-in. The auto-tweet and auto-Facebook are the only ways I &amp;ldquo;distribute&amp;rdquo; the posts and that gives me enough feedback to keep me happy.&amp;nbsp;Oh and in case you were wondering, yes, blog comments are dead, I get far more replies to each post as Tweets or Facebook replies. Pity Posterous can&amp;rsquo;t track those and show them in addition to retweet counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>