<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Our-Replacement-For-Sky-Tv-Cost-E99-Ariva-120-No-Monthly-Fees on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/our-replacement-for-sky-tv-cost-e99-ariva-120-no-monthly-fees/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Our-Replacement-For-Sky-Tv-Cost-E99-Ariva-120-No-Monthly-Fees on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 07:49:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/our-replacement-for-sky-tv-cost-e99-ariva-120-no-monthly-fees/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Our replacement for Sky TV cost 99. Ariva 120. No monthly fees!</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/our-replacement-for-sky-tv-cost-e99-ariva-120-no-monthly-fees/our-replacement-for-sky-tv-cost-e99-ariva-120-no-monthly-fees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 07:49:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/our-replacement-for-sky-tv-cost-e99-ariva-120-no-monthly-fees/our-replacement-for-sky-tv-cost-e99-ariva-120-no-monthly-fees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Our replacement for Sky TV cost \u008099. Ariva 120. No monthly fees!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the kids complained about the removal of Sky. A lot. There are only so many Charlie and Lola episodes you can watch on YouTube, particularly the ones in Finnish. &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The intention was to get that very highly recommended Humax Freesat box on Amazon but it&amp;#39;s bloody pricey and we weren&amp;#39;t sure we needed all of the features. Then the very kind &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gpelly&#34;&gt;@gpelly&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter mentioned the hugely impressive Ferguson Ariva 120 Combo. I love finding absolute bargains that don&amp;#39;t disappoint and this ticks both of those boxes. It is a FTA satellite receiver and DTT receiver. So it can handle Freesat and Saorview programmes. At 99 on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.satellite.ie/acatalog/HD_Ariva_120_Combo_Box.html#aFerguson120Combo&#34;&gt;Satellite.ie&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#39;s a complete steal.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Ours arrived yesterday and already the kids are happier. I plugged a spare 500GB USB HDD into it and it does full PVR functionality too. You can watch DTT and record Satellite or vice-versa. It does 720p and 1080i and can upscale SD content. It has a LAN port, SCART and HDMI. I&amp;#39;m intrigued by the LAN port. If they could add UPNP or SMB browsing then you have a pretty bloody decent streaming media player thrown in too. It&amp;#39;s also tiny. Software upgrade is easily done using USB.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;There is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boards.ie/vbulletin/showthread.php?t=2056284276&#34;&gt;massivethread about it on boards.ie&lt;/a&gt; with tons of support from Tony in Satellite.ie.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freesat.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Freesat programme list&lt;/a&gt; is not massive but is not bad. As it&amp;#39;s not an official Freesat box, there is no EPG, so you only have now/next for the programme info. CBBC, CBeebies, CITV and daytime TV on some of the other channels should keep the kids from going completely mad.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;I can&amp;#39;t report on DTT performance as our aerial doesn&amp;#39;t seem to be working right now. It is pointing into a tree in the general direction of the old Carrigaline repeater so I&amp;#39;ll need to twist it to point to a local digital mast and test it too.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;And all without any Rupert tax to pay. I&amp;#39;m already thinking of getting a second one.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>