<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote-Control-Implementation-For-An-Rc-Car-Part-1s on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/remote-control-implementation-for-an-rc-car-part-1.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remote-Control-Implementation-For-An-Rc-Car-Part-1s on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 15:04:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/remote-control-implementation-for-an-rc-car-part-1.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Control implementation for an RC Car - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/remote-control-implementation-for-an-rc-car-part-1/remote-control-implementation-for-an-rc-car-part-1.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 15:04:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/remote-control-implementation-for-an-rc-car-part-1/remote-control-implementation-for-an-rc-car-part-1.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Remote Control implementation for an RC Car - Part 1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many ways you can add remote control to a project. Off the shelf modules; Bluetooth; 2.4GHz NRF24L01+ transceivers; 433MHz/434Mhz modules or even Infra-red.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/remote_control.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-1059&#34; alt=&#34;remote_control&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/remote_control-1024x576.jpg&#34; width=&#34;584&#34; height=&#34;328&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan with &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.net/progress-so-far-with-a-kids-e21-self-assemble-remote-control-car/&#34;&gt;our ZL-4 el-cheapo RC&lt;/a&gt; car was to use an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elecfreaks.com/1999.html&#34;&gt;Elecfreaks Joystick Shield&lt;/a&gt;, an Arduino board and the&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.ie/itm/1X-NRF24L01-2-4GHz-Antenna-Wireless-Transceiver-Module-For-Microcontroller-WST-/271133536748?ssPageName=ADME:L:OC:IE:3160#ht_5792wt_1385&#34;&gt;NRF24L01+&lt;/a&gt; modules mainly because [a] the joystick shield has a connector for one and [b] I want to use them in another potentiallycommercialproject and thought it would be a good learning exercise. They are also stunningly cheap at 1.26,includingshipping, for each transceiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Idiscovered that the Adafruit Motor Shield on the RC car uses up a ton of the pins on the Arduino and makes it very hard to add theNRF24L01+. In particular it uses the SPI pins which you need to talk to theNRF24L01+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went with Plan B which was the 433Mhz modules. These things are fab. They work in the unregulated ISM band like most weather stations etc and, like the NRF24L01+,are gob-smackingly cheap - 1.97 for &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.com/p/diy-433mhz-wireless-receiving-module-for-arduino-green-149252?Utm_rid=73941134&amp;Utm_source=affiliate&#34;&gt;the receiver&lt;/a&gt; and 2.14 for &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.com/p/433mhz-wireless-transmitter-module-superregeneration-for-arduino-green-149254?Utm_rid=73941134&amp;Utm_source=affiliate&#34;&gt;the transmitter&lt;/a&gt;. When I see people creating really simple projects but with 2x 20+ Zigbee modules, I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 433MHz modules main advantage relative to theNRF24L01+ is that they can cover longer distances with a properly setup aerial. The main disadvantages are that they generally need that aerial, they have a very low bit-rate and you have to deal with most of the error correction etc yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What transforms these modules into something pretty spectacular is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airspayce.com/mikem/arduino/&#34;&gt;VirtualWire&lt;/a&gt; library for Arduino. This takes care of all the low-level transmit/receive code and you have to do little more than the equivalent of a print statement. Just think about this. You can send any information you like over hundreds of feet using 4 worth of electronics by simply calling:
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;vw_send((uint8_t *)msg, strlen(msg));&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
No Wifi or SMS needed! Of course this is a broadcast message and anyone can pick it up but who cares.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one thing we do have to figure out is what happens when multiple devices are broadcasting locally. Will they interfere with each other? I know VirtualWire has CRC checking but that&amp;rsquo;s not much use if every message is corrupt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the remote control I have created an extremely simplistic &amp;ldquo;protocol&amp;rdquo;. The transmitter sends out the following every 200ms:
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;XnnnnYnnnnAnBnCnDn&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Where Xnnnn is the X-axis of the joystick from 0 to 1024, Ynnnn is the Y-axis of the joystick from 0 to 1024, An is button-A 0 or 1, Bn is button-B 0 or 1, Cn is button-C 0 or 1 and Dn is button-D 0 or 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/remote_control2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-1063&#34; alt=&#34;remote_control2&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/remote_control2-1024x748.jpg&#34; width=&#34;584&#34; height=&#34;426&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now successfully receiving and interpreting those messages on the RC car and doing forward/reverse. The bit we have to figure out is turning, as the car doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any steering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More updates in a few days when we crack that nut. And I&amp;rsquo;ll obviously have to add some sort of &amp;ldquo;addressing&amp;rdquo; for the scenario where more that one RC car is being controlled in the house.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>