<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>I-Need-Boxee-For-Families on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/i-need-boxee-for-families.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in I-Need-Boxee-For-Families on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 11:46:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/i-need-boxee-for-families.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I need Boxee for Families</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/i-need-boxee-for-families/i-need-boxee-for-families.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 11:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/i-need-boxee-for-families/i-need-boxee-for-families.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;I need Boxee for Families&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Boxee_small&#34; height=&#34;251&#34; src=&#34;http://getfile1.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/conoroneill/tDnTJMdCVYOVjK80R3E8Lr1c8B7LhRRuwXw763UVrErreq7XbRAaCuGMJmww/boxee_small.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve been a Boxee fanatic since I first discovered it as a replacement for our old XBoxes+XBMC which can&amp;#39;t handle H.264 video. The app gets better and better and I&amp;#39;m thrilled they have launched a standalone box. Quick aside: Any chance they&amp;#39;d sell the Boxee remote for us PC owners? I bloody hate the generic MCE one we have. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Living 2km from an Irish town centre as we do, video streaming is not an option after 7pm. The two tin cans + string that passes for Eircom 7 Mbs broadband can&amp;#39;t sustain anything once ADSL contention goes up at night. So for the moment, we use Boxee as the ultimate local media player. It can handle anything we throw at it. As I&amp;#39;ve said before, its capability and usability make a mockery of the many years that have gone into Windows Media Center.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;But, and it&amp;#39;s a big but, Boxee (and probably every other Media Center) are clearly developed by single childless people who have 100% control over their TVs. So whilst I love the Twitter and Facebook integration and the bookmarklet to remember stuff to watch, I am constantly aware that a 7 year old child may be checking out what is being posted to our Boxee setup.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Of course there are Boxee user logins. And I bet they get about as much use as multiple Windows logins i.e. none. Who the hell wants to go through a logout/login cycle just to watch TV? &amp;quot;Daddddddddd, what&amp;#39;s the password again?&amp;quot;. Microsoft even tried to simplify things with the user-switcher in Windows but that takes an eternity too.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;So what&amp;#39;s the solution? I dunno! The only thing I can think of are those fingerprint readers that some laptops had a few years back. Build that into the remote and automatically show me my Boxee view without any messing with login/logout/password.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Any other ideas for dealing with this in a practical, 5 kids in a house, way?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>