<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The-And100-Android-Box-Is-Perfect-For-Netflix-Rte-Player-Etcs on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-and100-android-box-is-perfect-for-netflix-rte-player-etc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The-And100-Android-Box-Is-Perfect-For-Netflix-Rte-Player-Etcs on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 19:43:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/the-and100-android-box-is-perfect-for-netflix-rte-player-etc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The AND100 Android Box is perfect for Netflix, RTE Player etc</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-and100-android-box-is-perfect-for-netflix-rte-player-etc/the-and100-android-box-is-perfect-for-netflix-rte-player-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 19:43:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/the-and100-android-box-is-perfect-for-netflix-rte-player-etc/the-and100-android-box-is-perfect-for-netflix-rte-player-etc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;The AND100 Android Box is perfect for Netflix, RTE Player etc&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tvtrade.ie/&#34;&gt;TV Trade&lt;/a&gt; very kindly gave me an AND100 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tvtrade.ie/android-box.html&#34;&gt;Android Box&lt;/a&gt; before Christmas and I&amp;rsquo;m only now finally getting around to reviewing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Clipboard-1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1256 aligncenter&#34; alt=&#34;Clipboard-1&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Clipboard-1.jpg&#34; width=&#34;496&#34; height=&#34;299&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping an eye on the whole Android TV Stick/Box market for a while. There are so many out there, it is almost impossible to pick one and I haven&amp;rsquo;t been overly impressed with the sticks due to all the compromises involved in getting everything into such a small form factor. Wifi performance in particular seems to be a failing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This AND100 box is a different kettle of fish. It&amp;rsquo;s a box for a start! It also has wired Ethernet as well as built in Wifi. It comes with a couple of USB ports so you can add a Wireless Keyboard and USB harddisk if you wish. In addition to the usual HDMI, it also has Composite out if you have an older TV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only real difference from standard Android 4.x is that they&amp;rsquo;ve added a pretty hokey home page which I could really do without. But so far that&amp;rsquo;s the biggest complaint I can make. It has full Android Play Store and it was a doddle to install Netflix, RTE Player, iPlayer etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Android hasn&amp;rsquo;t been optimised for non-touch devices so I was surprised how well the simple IR minimal remote control works. Up/Down/Left/Right play/pause etc is really all you need for most of the Media Apps. Netflix works particularly well compared to the PC version I&amp;rsquo;m used to. The extra wireless keyboard with touchpad deals with those times when you need text input and you find the on-screen keyboard is too much hassle. In an ideal world both remotes would be merged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the media Apps I tried like Netflix worked like a charm which is hardly surprising since it has a dual-core 1.5GHz CPU. The only let-down was XBMC which still doesn&amp;rsquo;t have hardware h264 decoding on most Android devices and struggled to play 720p stuff across the network. But that is more down to XBMC and I hope to see that sorted for most devices in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst you can get Roku boxes etc to play Netflix, they are extremely limited and obviously don&amp;rsquo;t run Android. In fact they currently don&amp;rsquo;t even have YouTube. And whilst I love XBMC/RaspBMC on Raspberry Pi, things like YouTube take an eternity to load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried any games on the box so I don&amp;rsquo;t know how the UI would work but there is nothing stopping you from giving it a lash. Whilst I almost never watch RTE, I did try out the RTE Player and it worked perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s a great piece of kit and it should be a trivial exercise to install OpenVPN and connect to your VPN provider so you can access the likes of local BBC or Hulu on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price is actually great compared to many of the Android sticks out there which are far less functional. You also know that if anything goes wrong, you have a local supplier and you won&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with the black hole that is returns to China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if only House of Cards Season 2 would hurry up and get here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>