<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Happy-30th-Birthday-Zx-Spectrum-Heres-Mine-Still-In-Actions on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/happy-30th-birthday-zx-spectrum-heres-mine-still-in-action/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Happy-30th-Birthday-Zx-Spectrum-Heres-Mine-Still-In-Actions on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 22:22:39 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/happy-30th-birthday-zx-spectrum-heres-mine-still-in-action/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 30th Birthday ZX Spectrum - Here&#39;s mine, still in action</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/happy-30th-birthday-zx-spectrum-heres-mine-still-in-action/happy-30th-birthday-zx-spectrum-heres-mine-still-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 22:22:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/happy-30th-birthday-zx-spectrum-heres-mine-still-in-action/happy-30th-birthday-zx-spectrum-heres-mine-still-in-action/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Happy 30th Birthday ZX Spectrum - Here&amp;rsquo;s mine, still in action&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course I write too much about the ZX Spectrum. Heck look at the header image. But when a tiny little computer has such an impact on your life, it deserves your attention, even 30 years later. I hope all of you who built the first iPhone Apps have held on to your first device and do the same in 25 years time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/zx_1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-699 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;zx_1&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/zx_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;391&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My only disappointment today is that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raspberrypi.org/&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; yet to sit alongside it as its spiritual successor.I honestly think, with the right support, the Raspberry Pi could be this generation&amp;rsquo;s ZX Spectrum. Affordable by most people in the midst of a worldwide recession.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why don&amp;rsquo;t the BBC, RTE, DR and all the other taxpayer-supported European TV stations come together and do a 2012 version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Computer_Programme&#34;&gt;The Computer Programme&lt;/a&gt;, based around a boxed version of the RPi? Heck, make it part of the school curriculum. Yeah, really showing my age there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put together this video today showing my old Speccy (vintage late-1982) still working, still making me smile. I had to cheat and use a laptop to do the game loading as I can&amp;rsquo;t find any of my old tapes and the Aiwa walkman isn&amp;rsquo;t even 1980s vintage anyway. My old Lloytron mono tape recorder is AWOL too. Otherwise, all totally authentic stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lqpFDG5n4tc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note, if anyone has any idea why the colour is off on the TV output and how I might fix it, please leave a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a read of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-17776666&#34;&gt;this great interview&lt;/a&gt; with some of the Spectrum&amp;rsquo;s designers over on the BBC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again Sir Clive. And an ever bigger thanks to my parents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>