<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grant-Benefit-Of-Basing-Bes-Backed-Business-In-West-Corks on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/grant-benefit-of-basing-bes-backed-business-in-west-cork/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grant-Benefit-Of-Basing-Bes-Backed-Business-In-West-Corks on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 14:22:37 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/grant-benefit-of-basing-bes-backed-business-in-west-cork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Grant Benefit of Basing BES-backed Business in West Cork</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/grant-benefit-of-basing-bes-backed-business-in-west-cork/grant-benefit-of-basing-bes-backed-business-in-west-cork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2010 14:22:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/grant-benefit-of-basing-bes-backed-business-in-west-cork/grant-benefit-of-basing-bes-backed-business-in-west-cork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Grant Benefit of Basing BES-backed Business in West Cork&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The horror that is broadband in West Cork means that heavy-duty internet-centric businesses willprobablyavoid being based here. However we did run into a little-known business advantage last week.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;We are prepping to exhibit LouderVoice at a major show in the UK soon (details to be announced shortly) and we contacted Enterprise Ireland to see what supports/grants they offer to companies doing this. It turns out that they usually pay 50% of any expenses incurred which is fantastic. It is also one of the few areas in EI that has not seen a major reduction due to its importance to export-oriented companies.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;However the EU did create one small glitch which is that companies in receipt of BES or SCS investment don&amp;#39;t get the full 50% and we are one of those companies. If we were in Cork City (or Dublin, Kildare, Wicklow and Meath), the grant would be reduced to 25%. But because West Cork is seen as a &amp;quot;disadvantaged&amp;quot; area along with the rest of rural Ireland, we get a 40% grant. Score 1 for Bandon! Next they&amp;#39;ll give us FTTH.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>