<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>One-Guy-In-Netherlands-Vs-Nokiamicrosofts on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/one-guy-in-netherlands-vs-nokiamicrosoft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in One-Guy-In-Netherlands-Vs-Nokiamicrosofts on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 13:31:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/one-guy-in-netherlands-vs-nokiamicrosoft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>One guy in Netherlands vs Nokia&#43;Microsoft</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/one-guy-in-netherlands-vs-nokiamicrosoft/one-guy-in-netherlands-vs-nokiamicrosoft/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 13:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/one-guy-in-netherlands-vs-nokiamicrosoft/one-guy-in-netherlands-vs-nokiamicrosoft/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;One guy in Netherlands vs Nokia+Microsoft&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wow, it looks like I was the only person on the planet to write anything nice about Nokia moving to Windows Phone 7. One point I did make was that they have to move fast. A phone by the summer really is a necessity. But Nokia&amp;rsquo;s problems in recent years have always seemed to boil down to execution. Strategy by the bucket-full but bugger-all follow-through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elop said on stage that they will ship WP7 phones in volume in 2012. I hope that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean people will have to wait a year for a phone. I mentioned in my last post that a quick port of WP7 to the N8 (with the mandated CPU and memory boost) would probably sell well. Now I seriously doubt whether they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compare that to the situation on Android. Google released Gingerbread v2.3 on the Nexus S only before Christmas. Within weeks we had community ports for most of the major phones. I am currently downloading GingerVillain v1.0 for my HTC Desire. That&amp;rsquo;s Gingerbread with lots of knobs-on added by the Android community and packaged by a single guy in the Netherlands.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://getfile6.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2011-02-11/onaFzHqsgCkiqBCbpytIpBodpFstHqqAcsykvwxInivawdeApGGksClvigJr/gingervillain.png.scaled1000.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Gingervillain&#34; height=&#34;291&#34; src=&#34;http://getfile2.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2011-02-11/onaFzHqsgCkiqBCbpytIpBodpFstHqqAcsykvwxInivawdeApGGksClvigJr/gingervillain.png.scaled500.png&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if the same was possible with WP7 and the N8? But with two giant bureaucracies trying to work together, 2012 may even be optimistic. I wonder if there are drivers available for the N8 hardware? Imagine if some hackers got Android running on the N8 (like the N900) before Nokia ported WP7? That would say it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>