<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Changing-Over-To-A-Bluetooth-Car-Stereo-To-Work-With-Your-Phones on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/changing-over-to-a-bluetooth-car-stereo-to-work-with-your-phone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Changing-Over-To-A-Bluetooth-Car-Stereo-To-Work-With-Your-Phones on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 09:10:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/changing-over-to-a-bluetooth-car-stereo-to-work-with-your-phone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing over to a Bluetooth car stereo to work with your phone</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/changing-over-to-a-bluetooth-car-stereo-to-work-with-your-phone/changing-over-to-a-bluetooth-car-stereo-to-work-with-your-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 09:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/changing-over-to-a-bluetooth-car-stereo-to-work-with-your-phone/changing-over-to-a-bluetooth-car-stereo-to-work-with-your-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Changing over to a Bluetooth car stereo to work with your phone&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I blogged about this before ages ago but had some recent questions on it so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d do a quick update. If, like me, you drive an old car, your car stereo probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an audio jack and almost definitely doesn&amp;rsquo;t have bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a Ford from 1999 onwards then you have the added problem of a double height stereo whose CD player is probably knackered at this stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out to be quite easy to replace any of the above with a dirt cheap stereo from Lidl or Aldi which gives you A2DP high-quality bluetooth audio through your car speakers when you pair your smartphone to it. As an added bonus you get an acceptable hands-free system built in too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The steps are as follows:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Buy one of the bluetooth units from Aldi or Lidl. I see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lidl.ie/cps/rde/xchg/SID-2D79591D-3B4CF92F/lidl_ri_ie/hs.xsl/index_17063.htm&#34;&gt;Lidl has one of them for sale&lt;/a&gt; this Monday.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Find your car stereo extraction keys or, if you can&amp;rsquo;t, find 4 thin screwdrivers (jewellers ones work on many cars)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll need two or threeadapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The ISO audio/power one. e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.incarexpress.co.uk/view_product.php?partno=PC2044&#34;&gt;This one works&lt;/a&gt; for Opel Astra&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The antenna one. e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.incarexpress.co.uk/view_product.php?partno=PC5100&amp;amp;gclid=CMm0me6x46..&#34;&gt;This one works&lt;/a&gt; for lots of cars&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Potentially a fascia blank-plate if you have a double-height Ford stereo. e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ebay.co.uk/itm/Ford-Focus-Fascia-Facia-Panel-Adapter-Plate-Surround-/250595006485?pt=UK_CarsParts_Vehicles_CarParts_SM&amp;amp;hash=item3a58a05815#ht_2340wt_1139&#34;&gt;this one for Ford Focus on eBay&lt;/a&gt; (many sellers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pop the stereo out of the dashboard using the keys or screwdrivers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Disconnect the cables at the back making sure none of them fall down into the bowels of the car&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Potentially remove the flimsy metal cage that held the stereo in if it was a third party brand e.g. the old Blaupunkt in my wife&amp;rsquo;s Zafira&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Insert the fascia blank-plate if you have a Ford&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Connect power/audio to the new stereo etc using the ISO adapter&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Connect the antenna to the new stereo using its adapter&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Wiggle it all in. This can take a while. Mondeo as a doddle, Zafira was a horror&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Done!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Now you can pair your phone with the stereo and play all your music/podcasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only word of warning is that the radio reception on our two Lidl/Aldi ones is rubbish in West Cork compared to the factory-fitted models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>