<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>First-Two-Trivial-Parts-Of-Getting-App-Inventor-Working-On-Raspberry-Pi-Dones on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/first-two-trivial-parts-of-getting-app-inventor-working-on-raspberry-pi-done.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in First-Two-Trivial-Parts-Of-Getting-App-Inventor-Working-On-Raspberry-Pi-Dones on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 13:10:13 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/first-two-trivial-parts-of-getting-app-inventor-working-on-raspberry-pi-done.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>First two trivial parts of getting App Inventor working on Raspberry Pi done</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/first-two-trivial-parts-of-getting-app-inventor-working-on-raspberry-pi-done/first-two-trivial-parts-of-getting-app-inventor-working-on-raspberry-pi-done.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2012 13:10:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/first-two-trivial-parts-of-getting-app-inventor-working-on-raspberry-pi-done/first-two-trivial-parts-of-getting-app-inventor-working-on-raspberry-pi-done.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;First two trivial parts of getting App Inventor working on Raspberry Pi done&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing a small bit with the Raspberry Pi VM on VMware to see what&amp;rsquo;s possible and what isn&amp;rsquo;t. One thing I am eager to try when it arrives on the week of May 14th (YAY!), is to get App Inventor working on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three basic user parts to App Inventor. The browser-based Designer, the Java-based Blocks Editor and the Phone Emulator (if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a phone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I got the first two bits working with about 2 minutes work. All you need to do is install the OpenJDK. &lt;del&gt;SUN&lt;/del&gt;Oracle Java is not available yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/appinventor_raspberrypi.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;alignnone size-large wp-image-706&#34; title=&#34;appinventor_raspberrypi&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/appinventor_raspberrypi-1024x888.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;584&#34; height=&#34;506&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bit that will need more work is the emulator. I think. Ye see, I grabbed the code for the Linux version of the emulator and followed the simple instructions to build it. Then I saw it was building for i386 and of course the RPi is ARM-based. Damn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bit of poking around and I realised we were almost in a recursive loop. I was running ARM Linux in qemu i386 emulator on a Virtual Machine and I was trying to run an ARM emulator inside a another qemu i386 emulator inside that. Yes my head exploded too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then sense prevailed and I realised that Android is ARM and RPi is ARM, so do we need an emulator at all, or just an Android image compiled for ARM11 inside some sort of wrapper/container?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an old Embedded guy I should be all over this but I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten more than I ever learned about cross-compiling and building OS images. Anyone have any ideas on where to start? I popped a question on the relevant App Inventor Google Group too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course all of this may be moot if the 256MB of RAM and 700MHz CPU is not enough to support all of this. But it&amp;rsquo;s worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>