<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motorola-S10-Hd-Are-Brilliant-Bluetooth-Running-Headphones on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/motorola-s10-hd-are-brilliant-bluetooth-running-headphones.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motorola-S10-Hd-Are-Brilliant-Bluetooth-Running-Headphones on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 13:29:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/motorola-s10-hd-are-brilliant-bluetooth-running-headphones.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Motorola S10-HD are brilliant Bluetooth running headphones</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/motorola-s10-hd-are-brilliant-bluetooth-running-headphones/motorola-s10-hd-are-brilliant-bluetooth-running-headphones.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2012 13:29:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/motorola-s10-hd-are-brilliant-bluetooth-running-headphones/motorola-s10-hd-are-brilliant-bluetooth-running-headphones.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Motorola S10-HD are brilliant Bluetooth running headphones&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lovely people in Mobile Fun in the UK, home of a bajillion mobile and iPad accessories,contacted me recently. I&amp;rsquo;m a long-time customer of theirs and I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan. Their Dash Genie in-car phone holder is a wonderful thing that just works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They asked if I wanted to review anything on their site and I cheekily requested a pair of Motorola S10-HD headphones. They shot a pair over to me for free immediately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had them for a few weeks and they are just superb. Like a fool, I bought a pair of S9&amp;rsquo;s on eBay a few years ago. I didn&amp;rsquo;t suss that the only way they could be so cheap was if they were knock-offs. They fell apart in no time. These &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; S10-HD&amp;rsquo;s are in a different league altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/B2C-cnp2184-1-new-lg-US-EN.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-724 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;B2C-cnp2184-1-new-lg-US-EN&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/B2C-cnp2184-1-new-lg-US-EN.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;316&#34; height=&#34;295&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is unusual in that they basically clamp on to your head. Some people with particularly big noggins report that they are uncomfortable but I found after two uses that they fit perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/B2C-S10-3-new-US-EN.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-725 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;B2C-S10-3-new-US-EN&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/B2C-S10-3-new-US-EN.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;328&#34; height=&#34;200&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I wanted them was for running. I hate the normal in-ear wired headphones that fall out constantly and tie you in knots with the wires as you run. With these, I pair via Bluetooth A2DP to my HTC Sensation strapped to my arm and I listen to all my podcasts and music. It has volume and track selection buttons on one side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However it also works as a handsfree for the phone. If you are listening to music when an incoming call arrives, it mutes it and you can press a button to accept the call. I tested this paired to my laptop and made a few perfect quality Skype calls with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/B2C-S10HD-Global-packaging-life-US-EN.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-726 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;B2C-S10HD-Global-packaging-life-US-EN&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/05/B2C-S10HD-Global-packaging-life-US-EN.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;376&#34; height=&#34;369&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big test was this morning where I ran a sweaty Bandon 10km and listened to Kermode and Mayo&amp;rsquo;s movie reviews for an hour. I was chuffed that they worked perfectly, never slipped and did not hurt after an hour. I assume the same will be true when I do the Cork Half Marathon in June. Run Keeper is also able to temporarily mute the podcast and tell me my pace every 1km. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not much more to say. They work perfectly. They come with a variety of ear-plug sizes and they are great value. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using nothing else from now on when running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to the Mobile Fun crew. Still the first site I go to when I want to get something for my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE June 5th 2012: I ran the Cork Half Marathon yesterday with the S10-HD connected to my HTC Sensation. They worked beautifully. No battery issues, no drop-outs and my head wasn&amp;rsquo;t sore afterwards. Which is more than can be said about the balls of my feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>