<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>An-Evening-In-The-Company-Of-The-Delightful-Mr-Samsung-Galaxy-S4s on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/an-evening-in-the-company-of-the-delightful-mr-samsung-galaxy-s4.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in An-Evening-In-The-Company-Of-The-Delightful-Mr-Samsung-Galaxy-S4s on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 20:26:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/an-evening-in-the-company-of-the-delightful-mr-samsung-galaxy-s4.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>An evening in the company of the delightful Mr Samsung Galaxy S4</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/an-evening-in-the-company-of-the-delightful-mr-samsung-galaxy-s4/an-evening-in-the-company-of-the-delightful-mr-samsung-galaxy-s4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2013 20:26:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/an-evening-in-the-company-of-the-delightful-mr-samsung-galaxy-s4/an-evening-in-the-company-of-the-delightful-mr-samsung-galaxy-s4.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;An evening in the company of the delightful Mr Samsung Galaxy S4&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure you&amp;rsquo;re dying to know how I&amp;rsquo;m getting on with the S4. How many of you struggled to sleep last night with the anticipation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where to start? That screen, OMFG that screen. 5&amp;rdquo; of bright full 1080p HD. I played the classic Big Buck Bunny 1080p video and everything was crisper than crisp. I haven&amp;rsquo;t used it in bright sunlight yet but I&amp;rsquo;m sure it&amp;rsquo;s as crap as all modern phones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does the phone look? I couldn&amp;rsquo;t give two hoots. I buy phones as tools, not fashion accessories. Having said that, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be seen dead with a white one ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.samsung.com/global/microsite/galaxys4/&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-1017&#34; alt=&#34;gal_03&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/gal_03.jpg&#34; width=&#34;630&#34; height=&#34;640&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lightness of the S4 can be disconcerting when the buzzer gives haptic feedback but I&amp;rsquo;ll happily take lightness over a brick in my pocket any day. Oddly, the phone doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel big at all. In some ways it feels smaller than the HTC Sensation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I always hated HTC Sense and far prefer the Stock AOSP Android experience, I don&amp;rsquo;t find TouchWiz that objectionable. Given that I spend 95% of my time on a phone inside apps, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really affect me that much. It still has the powerful system-wide sharing features of Android and the still excellent (but now very cluttered) notification bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course it comes with a ton of Samsung junk Apps, just like HTC. I tried them all (Hub, Fitness, Story Book etc etc) but just can&amp;rsquo;t see the point of using single-vendor apps when I can use third-party ones from Google, Endomondo, Evernote or Amazon and bring everything with me if I switch to another vendor in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games, as you&amp;rsquo;d expect are blazingly fast and look gorgeous. I did find one or two that crapped out at launch tho. I&amp;rsquo;d love to know why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot of negativity about the &amp;ldquo;gimmick&amp;rdquo; features involving hand swipes and eye tracking but I was surprised to find that I really liked both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By tracking the location of your eye, it can auto-scroll web-pages etc when it notices your head tilt. I was easily able to start, stop and rewind a web-page using it. The big down side is that it only seems to work in Samsung apps. I&amp;rsquo;d love to see this in Twitter apps in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hand-waving is more gimmicky and allows you to scroll through photo albums etc. I just liked the ability to check the lock-screen for messages/missed-calls by waving my hand over the phone on my desk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to trying out Bluetooth 4.0 on my Fitbit. I don&amp;rsquo;t think the sync is currently working but they said on Twitter that they are going to test this week. I also don&amp;rsquo;t know if Android finally has BLE support to avoid big battery drain onconnecteddevices.I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of the idea of NFC for payments so I&amp;rsquo;ll give that a go when I have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another gimmicky thing that I like is the IR blaster built into the headphone socket. My eldest daughter thought it was pointless but I liked being able to change channel/volume on the TV without hunting for the remote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One annoyance, not specific to the Galaxy is the term &amp;ldquo;16GB&amp;rdquo;. This is total storage so you only start out with 9GB user storage, which I have already filled. Hence the absolute need for an SD card slot. I have a 32GB microSD on the way from Amazon. Side-note: This is a UHS-1 card which has 48Mbs throughput in certain cameras. Standard Class 10 SD is only 10Mbs. So I&amp;rsquo;d love to know if Samsung has implemented a UHS interface on the S4 or if it&amp;rsquo;s normal SD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big word of warning on the Dropbox integration. I just discovered that 4GB+ of the storage used on the phone was because it decided to auto-sync &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; from Dropbox. Everything! Eventually I ran out of storage on the phone and it stopped syncing. To avoid this, disable the &amp;ldquo;DocumentSync&amp;rdquo; feature in Settings-&amp;gt;Accounts-&amp;gt;Cloud. Stupid stupid default Samsung, what were you thinking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone is LTE and it should be fun to check out the download speeds the next time I&amp;rsquo;m in London. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m in Old Chapel, I can&amp;rsquo;t even get GPRS without major arm-waving. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the 30Mbs that Pat Rabbitte has personally guaranteed we&amp;rsquo;ll all have, as a minimum, by 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now, back to reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much chance to try out the camera. But the few initial pics were superb. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely be giving 1080p 30fps video a try out this week. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick example in bad light in my office:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/20130428_201032.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-1016&#34; alt=&#34;20130428_201032&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/20130428_201032-1024x576.jpg&#34; width=&#34;584&#34; height=&#34;328&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few other notes. The charger is 2 Amp and a useful compact size. The charger cable useless at a metre too short. The phone uses microSIMs so make sure you leave the shop the right kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try out some of the more obscure features in the next few weeks and then promptly forget about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vodafone will force you to &amp;ldquo;upgrade&amp;rdquo; to Red Essentials at a minimum if you are on an older cheaper plan. So I&amp;rsquo;m now paying 5 a month extra for 500MB a month less data. You stay classy Vodafone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One final note to Samsung. It would be a huge help if you&amp;rsquo;d do a phone-specific Samsung-branded sports armband, particularly since you now have this sports app. I&amp;rsquo;m really shooting in the dark with ordering on Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look, you can&amp;rsquo;t really go wrong with most mid to high end Android phones nowadays. If you get the S4 or the One or the Z or the Nexus4 or the whatever, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably be more than happy. The S4 packs an amazing raft of features into a pleasantly small package. I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to be happy with it for the next two years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>