<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>No-I-Dont-Want-To-Install-Your-Stupid-Hamstrung-Ipad-App-I-Want-Your-Web-Sites on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/no-i-dont-want-to-install-your-stupid-hamstrung-ipad-app-i-want-your-web-site.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in No-I-Dont-Want-To-Install-Your-Stupid-Hamstrung-Ipad-App-I-Want-Your-Web-Sites on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 08:16:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/no-i-dont-want-to-install-your-stupid-hamstrung-ipad-app-i-want-your-web-site.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>No I don&#39;t want to install your stupid hamstrung iPad App, I want your web-site</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/no-i-dont-want-to-install-your-stupid-hamstrung-ipad-app-i-want-your-web-site/no-i-dont-want-to-install-your-stupid-hamstrung-ipad-app-i-want-your-web-site.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2012 08:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/no-i-dont-want-to-install-your-stupid-hamstrung-ipad-app-i-want-your-web-site/no-i-dont-want-to-install-your-stupid-hamstrung-ipad-app-i-want-your-web-site.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;No I don&amp;rsquo;t want to install your stupid hamstrung iPad App, I want your web-site&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw a tweet along those lines the other day (sorry can&amp;rsquo;t remember who) and it really struck a chord. These &amp;ldquo;please install our App&amp;rdquo; pop-ups are infuriating in general on both Android and iOS. Every single vbulletin site I have gone to recently has done it. Why the hell would I want a separate App for every damned site I visit?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yesterday was the new nadir with Dropbox. Not only do you get the pop-up, they won&amp;rsquo;t let you visit information/download pages for any other platform on the iPad, they just auto-re-direct you to the iPad page!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For fucks sake Dropbox, I wanted to read what was involved in installing on a Linux server. Do I really need to use a desktop to read that page?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This finally revealed a very good reason for jailbreaking your iPad - you get a User-Agent Switcher and can pretend you are running Firefox on the Desktop. Also handy for those stupid sites who want to force a dumbed-down mobile web-site on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piss-poor reduced functionality Apps are the scourge of iOS and Android. Last weekend I ended up uninstalling the iPad Facebook App and now use the website in Safari just so I can have a goddammed Share button.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>