<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yeah-So-I-Got-An-Ipad-Let-The-Flaming-Commences on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/yeah-so-i-got-an-ipad-let-the-flaming-commence.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Yeah-So-I-Got-An-Ipad-Let-The-Flaming-Commences on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 18:07:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/yeah-so-i-got-an-ipad-let-the-flaming-commence.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Yeah, so I got an iPad. Let the Flaming Commence :-)</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/yeah-so-i-got-an-ipad-let-the-flaming-commence/yeah-so-i-got-an-ipad-let-the-flaming-commence.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2011 18:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/yeah-so-i-got-an-ipad-let-the-flaming-commence/yeah-so-i-got-an-ipad-let-the-flaming-commence.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Yeah, so I got an iPad. Let the Flaming Commence :-)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/-2g5CYow0vNo/TuD8rjgO7tI/AAAAAAAATcs/Q1Qe21XQ67g/s800/IMG_20111208_175717.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s for work, alright? Seriously tho.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First impressions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Great for doing demos. Spent all morning doing so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very good browser&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Love that smart cover thingy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Next buttons during initial setup are too small&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nice to see you don&amp;rsquo;t need a bloody computer any more to set it up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No idea what any of the icons in the email client do. Is one of them Delete or is that Archive? Where&amp;rsquo;s the Help button? Acutally repeat that question for every App&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email client itself is desperately clunky. Installing GMail now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The all-caps keyboard is so ridiculous I snort every time I use it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The App Store exiting every time I install an App is infuriating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With volume at zero it still makes noises for some notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can only install one App at a time - ever hear of multi-tasking?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All of the Twitter clients are utter garbage. Not one of them uses all the screen real-esate in any beneficial way. This is actually shocking. And Tweetdeck for iPad is gone. Big opportunity still there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No idea if iCloud is actually working. I assume so. The lack of a notification bar like Android is quite frustrating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accesses the mobile hotspot on my Android phone perfectly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Its auto-correct is even worse than Android. And the cancel pop-up is so tiny I have to tap it 4 or 5 times.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaking of which, I find the touch screen very unresponsive for things like the clear-button in the search box.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do any Apps use the lock-screen for things like weather? Or can they?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPN setup looks easy enough. Will do that later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect TV Second Screen. No doubt about it :-)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go on then, hit me with your favourite Apps. I&amp;rsquo;ve grabbed some of the interesting Top Selling free ones already. Thrilled to see Dropbox there. I also bought Instapaper and Keynote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the Asus Transformer Prime in the new year ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>