<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eircom-Vodafoneireland-And-Others-Need-Twitter-Status-Accounts on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/eircom-vodafoneireland-and-others-need-twitter-status-accounts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eircom-Vodafoneireland-And-Others-Need-Twitter-Status-Accounts on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 13:28:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/eircom-vodafoneireland-and-others-need-twitter-status-accounts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>@Eircom, @VodafoneIreland and others need Twitter Status Accounts</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/eircom-vodafoneireland-and-others-need-twitter-status-accounts/eircom-vodafoneireland-and-others-need-twitter-status-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 13:28:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/eircom-vodafoneireland-and-others-need-twitter-status-accounts/eircom-vodafoneireland-and-others-need-twitter-status-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;@Eircom, @VodafoneIreland and others need Twitter Status Accounts&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I find that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/eircom&#34;&gt;@eircom&lt;/a&gt; account on Twitter is generally extremely responsive and is the fastest way to get an answer to questions. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/VodafoneIreland&#34;&gt;@VodafoneIreland&lt;/a&gt; is very good too. However, they both (and O2, Meteor, emobile etc) need to implement status accounts, either a global one each or regional ones. So rather than tons of people badgering them about outages (in particular), we can go to the status account and see what&amp;#39;s going on. &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;But that&amp;#39;s just step one, since it only covers the stuff that the support people know about. Imagine if every Eircom tech had twitter on their phone/laptop and could post updates to those status accounts? We&amp;#39;d then know about stuff before it happens. For example, whatever is being done on our Eircom line at the minute would surely have been known about by someone in Eircom in advance.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;If we&amp;#39;d known about the planned work before it happened and not in the middle of a Skype call to a customer in the UK, then much hassle andembarrassmenttoday would have been saved by us and the Eircom support team on Twitter.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>