<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud-Kids on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/cloud-kids.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud-Kids on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 10:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/cloud-kids.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Kids</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/cloud-kids/cloud-kids.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/cloud-kids/cloud-kids.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Cloud Kids&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The kids use one of my old PCs to access all their favourite sites and print stuff off on a 10 year old Epson Inkjet. It&amp;rsquo;s a solid setup and they are happy with it. However, as it was a self-build, it never had a Windows licence and actually runs Ubuntu Linux.&lt;p /&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve always found it interesting that the kids could switch from XP to Windows 7 to Ubuntu on different PCs and laptops without comment. The reason of course is that they spend their entire time in the web browser. The old days of installing &amp;ldquo;educational software&amp;rdquo; from CD are long gone. It&amp;rsquo;s YouTube, Wikipedia, Nick Jr, Disney Playhouse, Webkinz etc etc. Everyone from the 3 y/o to the 10 y/o has that stuff mastered.&lt;p /&gt; However I find myself in one-time-only agreement with Steve Jobs on a particular topic and that&amp;rsquo;s Flash. Either Adobe figures out how to improve its performance by 10x and reduce it&amp;rsquo;s resource hit by a similar amount or it&amp;rsquo;ll go the way of Wordperfect within two years.&lt;p /&gt; Flash is a general resource pig on Windows but it renders Linux boxes unusable. Open three browser tabs on sites that have Flash-heavy ads and watch your dual-core machine grind to a halt.&lt;p /&gt;As a matter of principle I don&amp;rsquo;t disable ads in my browser. People have to make a living and that&amp;rsquo;s how many of them do. But I&amp;rsquo;m afraid, as of last week, I have turned on Adblock Plus on my Linux boxes. The results are astounding. Suddenly my browser is usable again. I can race through Google Reader and open 100 tabs with minimal slowdown. But on principle, I will tweak the filters soon to only block Flash ads and let through the text and image based ones.&lt;p /&gt; An hour ago I did the same on the kids&amp;rsquo; Linux box. Again, an incredible change. All those Flash-riddled sites are now fairly usable with the Flash ads turned off and the CPU dedicated to playing the game(s) on the sites.&lt;p /&gt; So Adobe is now responsible for reducing their customers&amp;rsquo; revenue by forcing people to disable functionality. &lt;p /&gt;I think we are going to see a fast and massive switchover from Flash for ads and kids&amp;rsquo; sites to HTML5+h.264 in the coming 12 months with that switchover led by The Steve. I&amp;rsquo;m really not sure how Adobe can prevent it except through FUD or a complete screwup of cross-browser cross-platform compatibility in HTML5.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>