<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>N8-Contest-Nokia-Cant-Even-Get-That-Rights on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/n8-contest-nokia-cant-even-get-that-right/</link>
    <description>Recent content in N8-Contest-Nokia-Cant-Even-Get-That-Rights on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 09:30:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/n8-contest-nokia-cant-even-get-that-right/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>N8 Contest - Nokia Can&#39;t Even Get That Right</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/n8-contest-nokia-cant-even-get-that-right/n8-contest-nokia-cant-even-get-that-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 09:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/n8-contest-nokia-cant-even-get-that-right/n8-contest-nokia-cant-even-get-that-right/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;N8 Contest - Nokia Can&amp;rsquo;t Even Get That Right&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&#34;&gt;
 &lt;blockquote class=&#34;posterous_medium_quote&#34;&gt;Welcome to the 2010 Calling All Innovators North America developer contest, presented by Nokia and AT&amp;amp;T. Were challenging developers to create new applications and games for the new Nokia N8 and future Nokia devices for consumers in the U.S. and Canada. With $10 million in cash, devices, and marketing prizes up for grabs, now is the time for you to take advantage of Ovi Stores global reach which gives you access to the worlds largest community of app-purchasing mobile consumers.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.callingallinnovators.com/10M/default.aspx&#34;&gt;callingallinnovators.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The N8 is the likely to be the last high-end Symbian phone. Nokia wants you to build an app for it and then enter a competition to win prizes.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They want you to build an app in the hope you&#39;ll have an upside.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They want you to risk your time and effort to help grow their business.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the same crap we saw with Palm and WebOS. If someone in Palm had had the sense to take $15m from their marketing budget and give $10,000 each to 1500 developers to build kick-ass apps, they might have succeeded.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nokia, if you want me to build an app for your dying platform, pay me in advance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>