<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mophie-Juice-Pack-Air-Is-Perfect-For-Marathons on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/mophie-juice-pack-air-is-perfect-for-marathons.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mophie-Juice-Pack-Air-Is-Perfect-For-Marathons on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 12:55:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/mophie-juice-pack-air-is-perfect-for-marathons.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Mophie Juice Pack Air is perfect for Marathons </title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/mophie-juice-pack-air-is-perfect-for-marathons/mophie-juice-pack-air-is-perfect-for-marathons.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 12:55:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/mophie-juice-pack-air-is-perfect-for-marathons/mophie-juice-pack-air-is-perfect-for-marathons.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Mophie Juice Pack Air is perfect for Marathons&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the niche problems with the iPhone 4 is full-length marathons. If you, like my wife, run 26 miles with music playing and Runkeeper recording all your stats, you will get to mile 25 and the battery will run out. Annoying to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tried a few el-cheapo chinese add-on battery packs that plug into the bottom but they rarely last more than a few weeks before going kaput. So a few months back in Dixons in Stansted I bit the bullet and handed over some serious cash for the 1500mAh &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mophie.com/mophie-juice-pack-air-iPhone-4-4s-battery-case-p/1145_jpa-ip4-blk.htm&#34;&gt;Mophie Juice Pack Air&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mophie.com/mophie-juice-pack-air-iPhone-4-4s-battery-case-p/1145_jpa-ip4-blk.htm&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-637 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;jpa-open-right3&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/jpa-open-right3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;339&#34; height=&#34;310&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
This is a full rubberised case with built-in lithium polymer battery. That battery tech is very cool as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be in the standard cell shape of traditional batteries. It means the phone ends up a bit taller, a bit wider and a bit thicker but not hugely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She used it last weekend in Maratona di Roma and it lasted the full race and well beyond. A big big thumbs up from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now all we need are the phone arm-band makers to up their game and start creating interesting ways of carrying these phones. The generic large Tune Belt strap we both use can barely fit a HTC Sensation or the iPhone+Mophie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote: Mophie, blocking the right-clicking of images on your site because they are copyrighted has to be one of the most stupid anti-online-marketing things I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in years. Also, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>