<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google-And-All-Of-Us-Should-Revolutionise-The-Interview-Process-Using-Sugrus on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/google-and-all-of-us-should-revolutionise-the-interview-process-using-sugru/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google-And-All-Of-Us-Should-Revolutionise-The-Interview-Process-Using-Sugrus on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 19:33:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/google-and-all-of-us-should-revolutionise-the-interview-process-using-sugru/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Google (and all of us) should revolutionise the interview process using @Sugru</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/google-and-all-of-us-should-revolutionise-the-interview-process-using-sugru/google-and-all-of-us-should-revolutionise-the-interview-process-using-sugru/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2012 19:33:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/google-and-all-of-us-should-revolutionise-the-interview-process-using-sugru/google-and-all-of-us-should-revolutionise-the-interview-process-using-sugru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Google (and all of us) should revolutionise the interview process using @Sugru&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve interviewed many many people myself over the years and only hired two real duds in that time. Mostly I did it with gut rather than asking people to write code on a whiteboard or drilling them on software lifecycle. My aim was to get a sense of &amp;ldquo;can I work with this person?&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;does it look like they have a creative streak?&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;have they any interest in software outside of work?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years ago, I even passed on the number one person in their year in Comp Sci in TCD because they ticked none of those boxes. They were just very smart, and I need a lot more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the Google interview process apart from what I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about the crazy number of sessions and the silly logic puzzles. If true, I&amp;rsquo;d worry that you end up with a ton of people who all have a very similar profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sugru.com/blog/google-commission-special-edition-sugru/&#34;&gt;Sugru&amp;rsquo;s post today&lt;/a&gt;about how Google commissioned them to do branded Sugru for Hiring Fairs suddenly made me realise that Sugru could totally change the way we all do interviews.&lt;img class=&#34;size-full wp-image-688 aligncenter&#34; title=&#34;google-googru-5601&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/google-googru-5601.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;373&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the usual CV trawl with the person, hand them a few packets of sugru and a box of bits and pieces. Give them 20 minutes to do something interesting. If they come up with nothing, don&amp;rsquo;t hire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What better way to see if someone really does have the type of creativity that is critical in this business?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>