<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Save-A-Few-Bob-On-Sky-Tvs on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/save-a-few-bob-on-sky-tv.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Save-A-Few-Bob-On-Sky-Tvs on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 14:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/save-a-few-bob-on-sky-tv.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Save a few bob on Sky TV</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/save-a-few-bob-on-sky-tv/save-a-few-bob-on-sky-tv.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2010 14:28:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/save-a-few-bob-on-sky-tv/save-a-few-bob-on-sky-tv.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Save a few bob on Sky TV&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know we are early adopters/geeks but I think what we are doing with media consumption is a reflection of what will happen in the mainstream in the next two years. &lt;p /&gt;Like many people we have been long signed-up to some stupid rip-off Sky package involving movies, multi-room and Sky+. it was costing north of 75 a month. We have slowly come to the realisation that we consume more and more content via the web with a simultaneous collapse in &amp;quot;normal&amp;quot; TV watching. I&amp;#39;d be surprised if I watch more than 2 hours a month of Irish TV but I still watch plenty of time-delayed BBC1/BBC2/Channel4 via Sky+. We haven&amp;#39;t watched any I/UTV channels in over two years. We&amp;#39;ve maybe watched one movie a month on SkyMovies and haven&amp;#39;t done BoxOffice in years (mainly because I disconnected the phone line to the box)&lt;p /&gt; But I do love my US TV and look forward to Boxee some day signing global content deals with all the networks to distribute their programming on a PPV basis worldwide. Total disintermediation of the distributors and the TV stations who buy their content. I don&amp;#39;t want my MTV, I want my IPTV. And I want it now. I want to see a list of House, Men of A Certain Age, Modern family etc etc etc on my Boxee box. Tick &amp;quot;Subscribe&amp;quot; beside each one and have them downloaded and paid-for within an hour of US TV broadcast. Hulu the way it should be. Except it&amp;#39;s Boxee.&lt;p /&gt; In preparation for this, I just rang Sky and dumped everything except standard programming like BBC and the Kids package. So Kids + Multi-room (for the kids) + SkyHD for 54 a month. New hardware but less dosh out every month. Result. And if the HD channels turn out to be a waste of time, we&amp;#39;ll drop that fee too.&lt;p /&gt; Rupert should start getting very very worried. One of these days he is going to wake up in Shady Pines with no-one paying for his newspapers&amp;#39; online content and only some die-hard sports subscribers on Sky.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>