<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My-Profile-On-Google-Buzz-Is-But-I-Aint-Happies on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-profile-on-google-buzz-is-but-i-aint-happy.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in My-Profile-On-Google-Buzz-Is-But-I-Aint-Happies on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 08:27:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/my-profile-on-google-buzz-is-but-i-aint-happy.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Profile on Google Buzz is...., but I ain&#39;t happy</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-profile-on-google-buzz-is-but-i-aint-happy/my-profile-on-google-buzz-is-but-i-aint-happy.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2010 08:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/my-profile-on-google-buzz-is-but-i-aint-happy/my-profile-on-google-buzz-is-but-i-aint-happy.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;My Profile on Google Buzz is&amp;hellip;., but I ain&amp;rsquo;t happy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, I&amp;#39;m in playing with Google Buzz on the Desktop and I don&amp;#39;t like it but I&amp;#39;ll keep at it for a while. It&amp;#39;s Friendfeed 2.0, and we all know what a roaring success that was.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;A bigger problem is the lack of GoogApps account support. I have driven all my mail through that account for the past three years. Now I have to revert to an old semi-dead GMail account to use Buzz. &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;So do I build up a network on Buzz there and in 3 months time Google announces &amp;quot;Yay we now support Google Apps in Buzz&amp;quot; and I have to start all over again?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Identity in Google in totally broken. I have a LouderVoice Goog Apps account and I have exactly the same email address as a Google Profile but not as GMail. So I can log in some places with GoogApps, some places with the Goog Profile and others with the old GMail account.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Even in Android, which does accept Goog Apps accounts, if I try and use that account in Google Voice on the Android phone, it tells me to piss off and use a GMail account. Ditto the Amazon MP3 store.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Does &lt;b&gt;anyone&lt;/b&gt;in Google talk to &lt;b&gt;anyone&lt;/b&gt; else?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Oh yeah.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/profiles/cwjoneill&#34;&gt;http://www.google.com/profiles/cwjoneill&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;But perhaps not forever.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;Any chance I can change that to conoro or conoroneill? Nah, didn&amp;#39;t think so. Too busy boiling the ocean to add useful features.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>