<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bmw-5-Series-Old-Or-New-For-My-Das on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/bmw-5-series-old-or-new-for-my-da.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bmw-5-Series-Old-Or-New-For-My-Das on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2010 13:52:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/bmw-5-series-old-or-new-for-my-da.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>BMW 5-Series. Old or new for my Da?</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/bmw-5-series-old-or-new-for-my-da/bmw-5-series-old-or-new-for-my-da.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2010 13:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/bmw-5-series-old-or-new-for-my-da/bmw-5-series-old-or-new-for-my-da.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;BMW 5-Series. Old or new for my Da?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My Da&amp;rsquo;s 12 year old BMW will fail its NCT unless he has 5 grand of work done on it so he has finally decided to get a new one. The new 520d and 525d are catching his eye. The advantage of the 525d is that it is available in March. The big disadvantage is a massive price uplift over the 520d. But he can&amp;rsquo;t really wait until July for the 520d to be released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The garage has some current model 520d&amp;rsquo;s in stock and he is wondering should he just get one of them instead. I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some research and I think he should but then I&amp;rsquo;ve never owned a Beemer so would appreciate advice from those in the know. My feelings are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He can get current 520d for a good deal if he negotiates hard (and waits for new shape to be launched)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nothing reported about the new 5 Series would matter to him (new shape, 8 speed auto, better iDrive, better suspension)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After 5 years, the three models will all be very similar in re-sale price. In particular, the 520d-&amp;gt;525d delta will have disappeared&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My only concern is that moving from 5L petrol to 2L diesel may be a leap too far for him. Some decent test drives on the new Waterford bypass should hopefully answer that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How is the 520d for refinement,&amp;nbsp;reliability, service cost etc? His old 7-Series is a lovely car but as reliable as a Trabant and spares cost a fortune.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or should he consider Merc/Audi? He&amp;rsquo;s been a BMW guy since the 80s when his job upgraded him from the vinyl-roofed Granada :-)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>