<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Parrot-Asteroid-I-Want-Something-Even-Simpler-Agains on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/parrot-asteroid-i-want-something-even-simpler-again/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Parrot-Asteroid-I-Want-Something-Even-Simpler-Agains on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 11:03:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/parrot-asteroid-i-want-something-even-simpler-again/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Parrot ASTEROID I want something even simpler again</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/parrot-asteroid-i-want-something-even-simpler-again/parrot-asteroid-i-want-something-even-simpler-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2011 11:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/parrot-asteroid-i-want-something-even-simpler-again/parrot-asteroid-i-want-something-even-simpler-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Parrot ASTEROID \u0096 I want something even simpler again&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Media_httpwwweurodroi_hwjbc&#34; height=&#34;355&#34; src=&#34;http://getfile3.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/conoroneill/AHblApFEJIphssytAckxjegtdzxqayxkcarufvmJgludBigeyFuFBtupynoz/media_httpwwweurodroi_HwJbc.jpg.scaled500.jpg&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eurodroid.com/2011/01/parrot-asteroid-android-for-your-car-stereo/&#34;&gt;eurodroid.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the best tech purchases I made over the past few years was a Lidl Bluetooth car stereo. My old built-in Ford RDS6000 no longer played CDs and never had a line-in so it had to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lidl (and Aldi equivalent) units are fantastic. They have line-in, USB, SD Card, CD Player, Radio, A2DP Bluetooth and a hands-free kit. All for about &amp;euro;80.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I was thinking a few months back that the Germans (and thousands of Chinese manufacturers) could build something better and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I have never used the CD player in that head-unit. I either plug in a USB stick with music, an SD card with music, or, most commonly, I pair my Android phone using Bluetooth and stream all my music and podcasts from that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CD player adds unnecessary weight, cost and complexity. What we need are better Bluetooth controls on these head-units. My wife&#39;s one can instruct my phone to go up and down a track but mine can&#39;t. I don&#39;t want a touch screen like the Parrot above, I want maybe 5 or 6 giant chunky buttons and/or a dial and I want the display to tell me the folder/artist/album/song being played on Bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically something like that Sony Ericsson LiveView but on a much bigger scale with the usual speaker connections etc at the back. I just find that messing with a touch-screen phone to change tracks/albums etc is a nightmare/dangerous when you are driving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. I recently discovered that my HTC Desire (and I&#39;m sure many other phones) can pair separately for media and calls. So I have media going to the car stereo but I have calls going to a bog-standard Plantronics headset. I just find that those I am talking to get better sound quality with the Plantronics. The phone is smart enough to mute media when a call is in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
 
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>