<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Another-Big-Brain-Dump-Of-Interesting-Tech-Bits-Over-The-Past-Few-Weeks on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/another-big-brain-dump-of-interesting-tech-bits-over-the-past-few-weeks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Another-Big-Brain-Dump-Of-Interesting-Tech-Bits-Over-The-Past-Few-Weeks on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 11:21:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/another-big-brain-dump-of-interesting-tech-bits-over-the-past-few-weeks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Another big brain dump of interesting tech bits over the past few weeks</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/another-big-brain-dump-of-interesting-tech-bits-over-the-past-few-weeks/another-big-brain-dump-of-interesting-tech-bits-over-the-past-few-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2013 11:21:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/another-big-brain-dump-of-interesting-tech-bits-over-the-past-few-weeks/another-big-brain-dump-of-interesting-tech-bits-over-the-past-few-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Another big brain dump of interesting tech bits over the past few weeks&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;line-height: 15px;&#34;&gt;Thrilled to find that Bluetooth on &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=2348272&#34;&gt;this Play Edition ROM&lt;/a&gt; for SGS4 works perfectly. I&#39;ve gone from 20% success rate auto-connecting to my Lidl car stereo to 100%, Finally!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nodeconf.eu/&#34;&gt;Nodeconf Europe&lt;/a&gt; is on in Waterford Mon-Wed. Incredible line-up of speakers. Superb IoT sessions set for Monday. A conference driven by expertise, not bullshit-artists hyping vapourware.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ordered an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.espruino.com/&#34;&gt;Espruino&lt;/a&gt; - run JS on an MCU&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;This --------&amp;gt; &amp;lt;-------- close to ordering a &lt;a href=&#34;http://technical.io/&#34;&gt;Tessel&lt;/a&gt; - moar JS on an MCU, this time with NPM support&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Waiting to order an &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.arduino.cc/2013/09/05/hands-on-the-arduino-yuns-bridge/&#34;&gt;Arduino Yun&lt;/a&gt;= Arduino + Wifi machine + bridge libraries&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Of course I had to back this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/556341540/pressy-the-almighty-android-button&#34;&gt;Pressy button&lt;/a&gt; for my Android phone. One of those slap-head projects that you can&#39;t believe you never thought of yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;What has happened to &lt;a href=&#34;http://ql.io&#34;&gt;ql.io&lt;/a&gt;? Was a very cool open source Node.js project from eBay for querying a variety of web-services using a SQL like language. Doing joins across data from multiple sites was damned impressive. Have they shut it down?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Finally got &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/conoro/status/374180519564836864&#34;&gt;Arduino talking to Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt; using two nRF24L01+ 2.4GHz devices. The libraries work great but it was the error-riddled blogposts by the author that made it take so long. I&#39;ll write up my own with the correct info soon. However it is not &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndrewGraley/status/374229759150264320&#34;&gt;Intrinsically Safe&lt;/a&gt;&#34;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;More MBP stupidity - horrible monochrome mini icons; favicons on Safari?; How do I discover that Safari is how to access the internet?; Caps Lock key in 2013 why?; but tiny arrow keys; no UK layout keymap for external keyboards; try to remember print-screen three-finger-salute; Magic Mouse hurts; DMG files - oh my god; Finder, oh hello 1989.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Apple-iPad-Keyboard-Dock-Package/dp/B0040HEMP8&#34;&gt;Apple keyboard dock for iPad&lt;/a&gt; is one of the worst pieces of industrial design of all time. Hilariously unstable and unusable. Going to hack a USB cable for it to see if it&#39;ll work as a PC keyboard since the buttons are nice.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Logitech-Ultrathin-Keyboard-Cover-iPad/dp/B00835UQK8/&#34;&gt;Logitech Ultra-thin keyboard case&lt;/a&gt; for iPad is one of the best pieces of industrial design I&#39;ve used. My Dad liking it a lot too. He may say bye bye to his heavy laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://fromscratched.nl/index.php/shrimpkey-maak-je-eigen-makeymakey-deel-1/?lang=en&#34;&gt;ShrimpKey&lt;/a&gt; - Take the Shrimp DIY Arduino and turn it into a DIY Makey Makey. Neat.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Two different HDMI to VGA adapters cause horrendous pulsating noise on the analogue audio output of all my Raspberry Pis. Anyone else seeing/hearing this?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Only getting a 65Mbs connection from SGS4 phone to a Wireless-N AP when I&#39;m right beside it. I have channel set not to overlap with any others. Where the hell is this mythical 300Mbs then?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://conoroneill.net/a-simple-tool-to-bulk-import-your-runkeeper-data-into-endomondo/&#34;&gt;Runkeeper to Endomondo import tool&lt;/a&gt; now supports Sports Tracker too&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonmadigan.com/2013/07/04/high-altitude-adventures-part-3/&#34;&gt;Very very neat helium balloon project&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Madigan&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;XBMC now supports &lt;a href=&#34;http://xbmc.org/xbmc-13-gotham-august-cycle/&#34;&gt;hardware video decoding on Android&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately not on Allwinner or AMLogic chips which is a total bummer as a large percentage of cheap devices use them. Fault lies totally with Allwinner and AMLogic. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xbmcandroid.com/2013/05/04/finally-a-stable-release-of-our-end-user-friendly-xaf-custom-build-of-xbmc-for-android-is-out/&#34;&gt;unofficial XBMC for Android&lt;/a&gt; works like a charm on my SGS4.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;No software application is complete until you can write code inside it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://plus.google.com/100132233764003563318/posts/JMM8j4sPbsk&#34;&gt;Code editor with Git support inside Chrome&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;I&#39;m sure I&#39;ve forgotten 10 other things.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>