<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Imagine-If-Facebook-Events-Allowed-Apps-For-Tv-Shows on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/imagine-if-facebook-events-allowed-apps-for-tv-shows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Imagine-If-Facebook-Events-Allowed-Apps-For-Tv-Shows on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 15:46:35 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/imagine-if-facebook-events-allowed-apps-for-tv-shows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Imagine if Facebook Events allowed Apps for TV Shows</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/imagine-if-facebook-events-allowed-apps-for-tv-shows/imagine-if-facebook-events-allowed-apps-for-tv-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2011 15:46:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/imagine-if-facebook-events-allowed-apps-for-tv-shows/imagine-if-facebook-events-allowed-apps-for-tv-shows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Imagine if Facebook Events allowed Apps for TV Shows&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was just reading how &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/appsblog/2011/apr/06/facebook-places-tv-industry?CMP=twt_gu&#34;&gt;Facebook wants TV channels&lt;/a&gt; to create Events for their entire EPG. It&amp;#39;s an absolutely superb idea and one that could seriously challenge Twitter&amp;#39;s dominance of live TV watching.&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;I would also be thrilled to see Late Late Show Friday and Sports Saturday disappear off to dedicated pages on Facebook instead of cluttering up my Twitter stream. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The story is a little confused between Events and Places. Can I check-in to an Event? Can Events be associated to a Facebook Places Page?&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;But it got me thinking. What if you had TV Show=PlacesPage -&amp;gt; N x Events=Episodes -&amp;gt; M x Apps per Event. So rather than just the standard Wall/Pics/Vids for Events, you could have the entire gamut of Apps? Now there&amp;#39;s some incredibly powerful hubs you could build around TV Shows.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;The other advantage of that is that unless I RSVPed an episode, it would keep it out of my main FB stream and I wouldn&amp;#39;t have spoilers on US TV Shows. It also means you could have one Event for an episode of Boardwalk Empire on HBO and another one for that episode on Sky Atlantic.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>