<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Amazon-Send-To-Kindle-Should-Be-Built-On-Rss-To-Replace-Google-Readers on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/amazon-send-to-kindle-should-be-built-on-rss-to-replace-google-reader.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Amazon-Send-To-Kindle-Should-Be-Built-On-Rss-To-Replace-Google-Readers on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:57:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/amazon-send-to-kindle-should-be-built-on-rss-to-replace-google-reader.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon &#39;Send to Kindle&#39; should be built on RSS to replace Google Reader</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/amazon-send-to-kindle-should-be-built-on-rss-to-replace-google-reader/amazon-send-to-kindle-should-be-built-on-rss-to-replace-google-reader.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 13:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/amazon-send-to-kindle-should-be-built-on-rss-to-replace-google-reader/amazon-send-to-kindle-should-be-built-on-rss-to-replace-google-reader.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Amazon \&amp;ldquo;Send to Kindle\&amp;rdquo; should be built on RSS to replace Google Reader&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a few mentions today of a new &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://techcrunch.com/2013/03/19/amazon-launches-send-to-kindle-button-for-web-developers-wordpress-blogs/&#34;&gt;Send to Kindle&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; button that you can add to your site/blog. It means people can send clips of your web content to their fave e-reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just struck me that Amazon is missing a serious trick with the Kindle here. An RSS-based reader which works on E-ink, Fire, Android and Cloud Reader could be something awesome. Whilst I use some web-clipping services like Pocket, I much prefer to subscribe to sites. Being able to click a Kindle button that I know is also an RSS button would make me very happy indeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that Google wants to kill RSS in favour of G+ in a classic but doomed Microsoft-style embrace/extend/extinguish, this could be a big opportunity for Amazon to both attract all the old GReader userbase and turn RSS into a mainstream Subscribe Button. Like we all thought RSS would be, back in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to have all my RSS feeds synced to my old-school Kindle. It&amp;rsquo;s ideal for medium-to-long-form content. Give it offline reading capability and I&amp;rsquo;m sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, I doubt I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding their current button to any of my blogs unless ShareThis adds it as a default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>