<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Get-Paid-Apps-On-Your-Android-Phone-In-Irelands on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/get-paid-apps-on-your-android-phone-in-ireland/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Get-Paid-Apps-On-Your-Android-Phone-In-Irelands on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 13:39:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/get-paid-apps-on-your-android-phone-in-ireland/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Paid Apps on your Android Phone in Ireland</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/get-paid-apps-on-your-android-phone-in-ireland/get-paid-apps-on-your-android-phone-in-ireland/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 13:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/get-paid-apps-on-your-android-phone-in-ireland/get-paid-apps-on-your-android-phone-in-ireland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Get Paid Apps on your Android Phone in Ireland&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing that has me incensed about Google is how the country that enables them to avoid tax on billions of dollars in revenue is generally paddy-last (pun intended) when it comes to app support.&lt;p /&gt;It was only in late 2008 that Google Maps finally showed more than one road in West Cork. Their most recent manifestation of this attitude is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://market.android.com/support/bin/answer.py?hl=en&amp;amp;answer=150324&#34;&gt;lack of paid apps&lt;/a&gt; for Irish users of Android phones. Whilst this was acceptable when only me and 5 others had unlocked US G1s, we have had mobile networks selling Android phones here for 3 months now. Grrrrrrr.&lt;p /&gt; Go into the Android Store on a G1 with a Vodafone or O2 Irish SIM and all you see are free apps.&lt;p /&gt;Now take that SIM out and pop in a Three UK PAYG SIM which you paid 10 for the last time you were in the UK and taa-daa, paid apps.&lt;p /&gt; And this is sitting in rainy West Cork with no Three signal so I&amp;#39;m roaming on the Vodafone Ireland network!&lt;p /&gt;As a test I just bought Pixelpipe Pro for $0.99. And for double kicks I tested the use of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.entropay.com/&#34;&gt;Entropay Virtual Visa&lt;/a&gt; to pay for it and used an Irish address and phone in Checkout. &lt;p /&gt; &lt;b&gt;And it worked!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;FFS Google, if all the bits are in place and working, including Google Checkout, what is the bloody problem?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>