<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The-Happy-Foot-Co-Is-Feeding-My-Vffs-Addictions on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-happy-foot-co-is-feeding-my-vffs-addiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The-Happy-Foot-Co-Is-Feeding-My-Vffs-Addictions on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 13:53:08 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/the-happy-foot-co-is-feeding-my-vffs-addiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Happy Foot Co is feeding my #VFFs Addiction</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-happy-foot-co-is-feeding-my-vffs-addiction/the-happy-foot-co-is-feeding-my-vffs-addiction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2011 13:53:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/the-happy-foot-co-is-feeding-my-vffs-addiction/the-happy-foot-co-is-feeding-my-vffs-addiction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;The Happy Foot Co is feeding my #VFFs Addiction&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s ridiculous I know. I average one pair of new footwear every two years. I wear shoes until they fall apart and then I buy one more pair. That&amp;rsquo;s now utterly changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought my Vibram Five Fingers Bikilas exactly one month ago. Running on a treadmill with them is genuinely like having new legs. Unfortunately, like a fool, I ran on the road only two weeks in and I&amp;rsquo;m still suffering with a pain in one foot. But I&amp;rsquo;m a convert and an evangelist already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one downside - they stink and washing only helps for a day or two. I wanted to wear them all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday I was in Dublin and after a really interesting mobile tech workshop, I wandered down to &lt;a href=&#34;http://happyfootco.ie/&#34;&gt;The Happy Foot Co&lt;/a&gt; on Liffey Street, off Henry Street. I remembered that the last shop I went into on Liffey St was Hector Gray&amp;rsquo;s when I was a kid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Happy Foot Co shop is amazing. Loads of different types of VFFs and a bajillion pairs of Crocs. I&amp;rsquo;ll be bringing the kids back soon to get their summer Crocs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two ladies running the place could not have been more helpful. They even offered to post down any pair that they didn&amp;rsquo;t have in stock. I wanted a pair for general day to day use that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t look too freakish. I tried on a few types including one of their new ones made of kangaroo skin. Sooooo soft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I went with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vibramfivefingers.com/products/Five-Fingers-KSO-Mens.htm&#34;&gt;KSO&lt;/a&gt;, the most popular men&amp;rsquo;s model. They are incredibly comfortable and equally good in a meeting or on a mountain (allegedly). They go beautifully with Black Tie, Pinstripe, Jeans, Shorts, Speedos or Thongs. I intend to try them in all those scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://getfile5.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2011-04-14/pECrvzxDzpnayemusvHxwqkhEbABkoptIEkvqwEqiIEIIgIFAviqynArFktA/IMG_20110413_091951.jpg.scaled1000.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Img_20110413_091951&#34; height=&#34;375&#34; src=&#34;http://getfile8.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2011-04-14/pECrvzxDzpnayemusvHxwqkhEbABkoptIEkvqwEqiIEIIgIFAviqynArFktA/IMG_20110413_091951.jpg.scaled500.jpg&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a bit of reading on VFFs and it looks like I&amp;rsquo;m doing the same thing as all n00bies; I&amp;rsquo;m running almost on the balls of my feet because of everything we&amp;rsquo;ve been told about heel-strikes being bad. One blogger likened it to looking like a bizarre ballerina. Of course I&amp;rsquo;ve been told many times of my striking resemblance to the Black Swan, ignoring my bigger boobs and my opposite eating disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/-QAUKQNdOXY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;390&#34; width=&#34;640&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two pairs of shoes in a month and I&amp;rsquo;m already thinking about a pair of Classics instead of flip-flops for my summer holidays. Next thing I&amp;rsquo;ll be watching Project Runway.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>