<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android-Need-Some-Hardware-Standards on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/android-need-some-hardware-standards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android-Need-Some-Hardware-Standards on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 18:10:52 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/android-need-some-hardware-standards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Android need some hardware standards</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/android-need-some-hardware-standards/android-need-some-hardware-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2010 18:10:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/android-need-some-hardware-standards/android-need-some-hardware-standards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Android need some hardware standards&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me is sick of my bitching and moaning about the closed nature of the iPhone. But that closed nature has one huge advantage; a global ecosystem of accessories has built up around it. From cases to speaker docks to headphones, suppliers work with fixed form factors and interfaces.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That ecosystem must now be worth hundreds of millions of dollars a year. It strikes me that Android could achieve the same thing but in an open way and with a focus on interfaces rather than form factors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first and most critical thing needed is an audio interface. This could be a software overlay on USB, it just needs to be defined. Currently Android phones can only connect to docks by 3.5mm jack and with no ability to change tracks etc.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google (and Moto with Droid?) have created phone-specific modules but surely that defeats the point of Android?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Whilst A2DP could be the solution, it&amp;#39;s still Bluetooth with all the pairing bullshit that it entails. Maybe NFC could sort that out?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend testing an iPod and iPhone dock. We used 2 generations of iPod and 2 generations of iPhone and they &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;just worked&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;. The poor HTC G1 dangling off the back on an audio cable looked like something from a previous century.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So how about it Google? Android should enable business opportunities, not get in their way.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>