<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Finally-Mhl-To-Tv-And-Bluetooth-To-Wiimote-On-Htc-Sensations on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/finally-mhl-to-tv-and-bluetooth-to-wiimote-on-htc-sensation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Finally-Mhl-To-Tv-And-Bluetooth-To-Wiimote-On-Htc-Sensations on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 18:12:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/finally-mhl-to-tv-and-bluetooth-to-wiimote-on-htc-sensation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally MHL to TV and Bluetooth to Wiimote on HTC Sensation</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/finally-mhl-to-tv-and-bluetooth-to-wiimote-on-htc-sensation/finally-mhl-to-tv-and-bluetooth-to-wiimote-on-htc-sensation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2012 18:12:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/finally-mhl-to-tv-and-bluetooth-to-wiimote-on-htc-sensation/finally-mhl-to-tv-and-bluetooth-to-wiimote-on-htc-sensation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Finally MHL to TV and Bluetooth to Wiimote on HTC Sensation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I know it&amp;rsquo;s a stupid thing to want to do but dammit, if it&amp;rsquo;s technically possible, we should at least try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most annoying things about the HTC Sensation is how HTC has hamstrung it with a brain-dead Bluetooth stack instead of the one provided by the chipset provider. This means it cannot do the HID profile to support keyboards, mice and Wiimotes. The only reason they do this is to shoehorn the horror that is HTC Sense on top of Android. Sense can&amp;rsquo;t even do landscape orientation of the home screen FFS!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you switch to one of the AOSP-based ROMs like Cyanogen, you gain a proper Bluetooth stack but, for the moment, you lose MHL, which means you cannot connect the phone via HDMI to your TV to play movies/games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But something changed recently with the latest HTC ROMs and I learned that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1098849&#34;&gt;Android Revolution HD ROM&lt;/a&gt;, which I have used many times in the past, now supports both MHL and HID. It is a community variation of the official Sensation ROM so it still has the Sense crap but it seems to be rock solid otherwise and has lots of benefits you miss with the official ROMs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is why I wanted to get both working:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;httpv://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1QWTkRwlhcM&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not my best ever video work, to put it mildly. But you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do the same you need:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;An MHL adapter&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A HDMI cable&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A Wiimote&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1098849&#34;&gt;Android Revolution HD ROM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.seleuco.xpectrum&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Xpectroid&lt;/a&gt; ZX Spectrum Emulator&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.mercury.inputmethod.wpad&amp;amp;feature=related_apps#?t=W251bGwsMSwxLDEwOSwiY29tLm1lcmN1cnkuaW5wdXRtZXRob2Qud3BhZCJd&#34;&gt;Wiimote Android App&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I also started investigating USB OTG on the Sensation this week. This is where you can use the USB interface to plug USB sticks, cameras, hard disks etc into the Sensation rather than the usual reverse. Yet again the hardware is capable of it, the standard drivers support it, but HTC has messed up the implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why the hell would you create devices with such amazing technical specs and then disable those features due to an obsession with a shitty software skin that offers no added-value to the end-user and which no-one has ever bought a phone for? Don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on the fact that the CPU in my phone is actually designed for 1.5GHz but ships clocked at 1.2GHz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>