<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Could-Bond-Traders-Use-Twitters on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/could-bond-traders-use-twitter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Could-Bond-Traders-Use-Twitters on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 10:54:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/could-bond-traders-use-twitter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Could Bond Traders use Twitter?</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/could-bond-traders-use-twitter/could-bond-traders-use-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 10:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/could-bond-traders-use-twitter/could-bond-traders-use-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Could Bond Traders use Twitter?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;#39;ve spent the past week with a column in Tweetdeck tracking #bailout and it makes for rivetting reading. On the one hand you have the official blather about &amp;quot;steady as she goes&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;everything is stabilised now&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Spain won&amp;#39;t need a bailout&amp;quot;. And on the other hand you have the aggregate of thousands of average people all saying the opposite. The trick is figuring out whether that aggregate is the wisdom of crowds or the same type of mass hysteria that created the bubble in the first place.&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p /&gt;I was also reading about &amp;quot;Bond Vigilantes&amp;quot; earlier and that dovetailed into reading Gladwell&amp;#39;s piece from 2002 onNassim Taleb and Victor Niederhoffer. In it he talked about the traders being glued to instant information and news. I guess that&amp;#39;s how Bloomberg made all his money with the terminals. I then just wondered if [a] anyone had built a Bloomberg-type app for Twitter that only looks at financial related news and more importantly [b] If anyone has built a sentiment analysis engine for financial opinion on Twitter to help direct their trades?&lt;p /&gt;&lt;div&gt;I&amp;#39;m imagining some interesting graphs showing some sort of Twitter Sentiment vs Bond Yields over time.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>