<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My-4-Years-Of-Android-Today-And-Irelands-First-Android-Apps on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-4-years-of-android-today-and-irelands-first-android-app.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in My-4-Years-Of-Android-Today-And-Irelands-First-Android-Apps on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 16:09:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/my-4-years-of-android-today-and-irelands-first-android-app.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My 4 years of Android today and Ireland&#39;s first Android App</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/my-4-years-of-android-today-and-irelands-first-android-app/my-4-years-of-android-today-and-irelands-first-android-app.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 16:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/my-4-years-of-android-today-and-irelands-first-android-app/my-4-years-of-android-today-and-irelands-first-android-app.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;My 4 years of Android today and Ireland&amp;rsquo;s first Android App&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today is the 4th anniversary of me paying $499 on eBay for a HTC G1, the first Android phone. Whilst some of my tech predictions over the years have been a little off (&lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; iPad) I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have got it more right with Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I heard about the Android project mid-2008, it was obvious Google wasn&amp;rsquo;t going into things half-heartedly. The G1 itself was a mixed bag. Ugly as sin but with a slide-out keyboard that I still love. Android 1.5 was rough but very functional for someone like me who spends their time on Google products like GMail. I still have the G1, running Android 2.3 and waking me up every morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I got the G1 was not for pointless bragging rights, it was because we had decided to build an Android App to show-off the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.loudervoice.com/products/enterprise-reviews/&#34;&gt;LouderVoice&lt;/a&gt; API to some Enterprise customers we were trying to land in the mobile space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created the spec and wireframes for the App and also figured out what extra features our API would need. The basic idea was &amp;ldquo;Review Anything Anywhere&amp;rdquo;. Essentially what Kevin Rose tried to do with Oink several years later. We both failed because no-one wants to do that :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marino Software in Dublin did the App coding for us and we finally launched &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.marinosoftware.loudervoice&amp;amp;feature=search_result&#34;&gt;Ireland&amp;rsquo;s first Android App&lt;/a&gt; in May 2009 for Android 1.6. It never had many users but it was a fantastic tool for showing potential business customers what our system could do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same back-end API is now used to power the reviews in the Riverdance Android and iPhone Apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I installed the old App again on my HTC Sensation running Android 4.1.2 and whaddyaknow, it still works! Sure the graphics-scaling is horrific on that big screen but you can still browse and submit reviews to our API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In those 4 years I&amp;rsquo;ve gone through a HTC G1, HTC Desire and HTC Sensation. I&amp;rsquo;ve also bought a ZTE Blade and Eken T02 tablet for others. There is no doubt that my next phone will be Android but sadly not HTC, as I insist on my phones having replaceable battery and SD card. At some point next year I&amp;rsquo;ll get a decent Android Tablet too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two upcoming areas I find exciting in the world of Android:
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultra-cheap single board Android computers in the style of Raspberry Pi&lt;/strong&gt;. Most of these are being sold as &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.com/s/android.html?category=191&#34;&gt;1080p media players&lt;/a&gt; but &lt;a href=&#34;http://apc.io/&#34;&gt;they can do a hell of a lot more&lt;/a&gt; for very little money. Which feeds into point 2.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware interfaces like IOIO&lt;/strong&gt;. Once I finish a couple of my fun Raspberry Pi and Arduino projects, I want to do some car projects using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sparkfun.com/products/10748&#34;&gt;IOIO&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than your phone/tablet just being for calls/music/GPS in the car, imagine if it was connected to a wide range of sensors and interfaces. Every car on the road acting as a generator of a wide range of interesting IoT data, all location-tagged and uploaded live over a mobile data connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
We&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way baby.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>