<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Check-Out-Scratch-For-Arduino-S4a-Easier-Electronics-For-Kids on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/check-out-scratch-for-arduino-s4a-easier-electronics-for-kids/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Check-Out-Scratch-For-Arduino-S4a-Easier-Electronics-For-Kids on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 18:40:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/check-out-scratch-for-arduino-s4a-easier-electronics-for-kids/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Check out Scratch for Arduino S4A. Easier electronics for kids</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/check-out-scratch-for-arduino-s4a-easier-electronics-for-kids/check-out-scratch-for-arduino-s4a-easier-electronics-for-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2013 18:40:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/check-out-scratch-for-arduino-s4a-easier-electronics-for-kids/check-out-scratch-for-arduino-s4a-easier-electronics-for-kids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Check out Scratch for Arduino (S4A). Easier electronics for kids&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of the Arduinoinitiative(is &amp;ldquo;initiative&amp;rdquo;the right word?), its programming language, Wiring, is still fundamentally C with most of its power but also most of its difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C was the fifth language I learned after ZX Spectrum BASIC, Forth, Z80 assembler and Fortran (spit). I then spent the next 13 years using little else. But here I am still struggling to read a number from a sensor, add it to an ascii string, send it over a wireless link and then convert that back to a number at the far end. The wireless link bit is trivial using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airspayce.com/mikem/arduino/&#34;&gt;VirtualWire&lt;/a&gt;, whilst the pain is all in the int/char/char */char []/String rubbish that would make most kids give up after an hour of hair pulling. And don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on Null termination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m very positive about both &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modk.it/&#34;&gt;Modkit&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://seaside.citilab.eu/scratch&#34;&gt;S4A&lt;/a&gt;. Modkit is a pay-for in-browser Scratch-like environment and I&amp;rsquo;m impressed with it, but I&amp;rsquo;ll blog about that another day. Today is about S4A which came out of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://citilab.eu/en/citilab/what-is&#34;&gt;Citilab team&lt;/a&gt; in Spain. It&amp;rsquo;s a modified version of Scratch that can interact with Arduino boards and electronics connected to it. I tested using an Arduino UNO and it worked perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/s4a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-large wp-image-1057&#34; alt=&#34;s4a&#34; src=&#34;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/conoroneill.net/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/s4a-1024x635.jpg&#34; width=&#34;584&#34; height=&#34;362&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting started is very easy. You &lt;a href=&#34;http://seaside.citilab.eu/S4AFirmware15.ino&#34;&gt;download some code&lt;/a&gt; for the Arduino which you put on the board using the usual &lt;a href=&#34;http://arduino.cc/en/Main/Software&#34;&gt;Arduino IDE&lt;/a&gt;. Then you &lt;a href=&#34;http://seaside.citilab.eu/S4A15.exe&#34;&gt;install S4A&lt;/a&gt;on your PC and run it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&#34;http://seaside.citilab.eu/s4a_basic_examples.zip&#34;&gt;some basic examples&lt;/a&gt;available to learn the core ideas.The examples all come with simple wiring diagrams which are appropriate for anyone with one of the UNO Starter Kits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;ll be interesting to see what we can do beyond simple button+led. I&amp;rsquo;m trying out some of the servo stuff with Oisn this afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>