<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nokia-Shafts-Millions-Of-N95-And-N95-8gb-Users on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/nokia-shafts-millions-of-n95-and-n95-8gb-users.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nokia-Shafts-Millions-Of-N95-And-N95-8gb-Users on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 14:15:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/nokia-shafts-millions-of-n95-and-n95-8gb-users.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Nokia Shafts Millions of N95 and N95-8GB Users?</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/nokia-shafts-millions-of-n95-and-n95-8gb-users/nokia-shafts-millions-of-n95-and-n95-8gb-users.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2010 14:15:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/nokia-shafts-millions-of-n95-and-n95-8gb-users/nokia-shafts-millions-of-n95-and-n95-8gb-users.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;Nokia Shafts Millions of N95 and N95-8GB Users?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_bookmarklet_entry&#34;&gt;
 &lt;blockquote class=&#34;posterous_long_quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt; Today, Nokia has responded making Ovi Maps 3 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nokia.com/maps&#34;&gt;available for the E71 and E66 too&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;posterous_medium_quote&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;People will be able to use Ovi Suite to side load the latest country maps onto their devices so they can enjoy offline map browsing alongside free navigation. The process of making the latest version of Ovi Maps available for existing devices is quite involved, but the team managed to include complete navigation functionality. Due to technical constraints in back porting the app to existing devices, unfortunately, it wasnt possible to offer further premium content such as Guide Michelin and Lonely Planet guides. These two devices will also be the last of our S60 3.1 and older devices to sport this version of Ovi Maps. But every upcoming Nokia Smartphone will come with free walk and drive navigation out of the box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;posterous_quote_citation&#34;&gt;via &lt;a href=&#34;http://thereallymobileproject.com/2010/04/ovi-maps-3-with-free-navigation-launched-for-nokia-e71-e66/&#34;&gt;thereallymobileproject.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;So it appears those millions of N95-* owners can go screw themselves as far as Nokia is concerned. Ovi Maps will continue to ask them for money for voice navigation whilst owners of newer crappier devices like the N97 get it for free.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know Nokia wants us all to upgrade and if they had a phone that was worth upgrading to, we probably would. But 399 for an N900 upgrade on Vodafone IE is a joke. And in any case, you can&#39;t get the new Ovi Maps for the N900.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well done Nokia, unless that story is wrong, this confirms my upcoming purchase of a HTC Desire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>