<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The-Utter-Imbecilic-Brain-Dead-Stupidity-Of-The-Amazon-App-Store-For-Androids on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-utter-imbecilic-brain-dead-stupidity-of-the-amazon-app-store-for-android.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in The-Utter-Imbecilic-Brain-Dead-Stupidity-Of-The-Amazon-App-Store-For-Androids on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 17:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/the-utter-imbecilic-brain-dead-stupidity-of-the-amazon-app-store-for-android.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Utter Imbecilic Brain-dead Stupidity of the Amazon App Store for Android</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/the-utter-imbecilic-brain-dead-stupidity-of-the-amazon-app-store-for-android/the-utter-imbecilic-brain-dead-stupidity-of-the-amazon-app-store-for-android.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 17:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/the-utter-imbecilic-brain-dead-stupidity-of-the-amazon-app-store-for-android/the-utter-imbecilic-brain-dead-stupidity-of-the-amazon-app-store-for-android.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;The Utter Imbecilic Brain-dead Stupidity of the Amazon App Store for Android&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: arial; font-size: small;&#34;&gt;We Irish Android early adopters railed against Google for their slowness in making paid Apps available outside of a tiny group of countries. Finally last year Google got their act together and we&amp;rsquo;re all now good buddies again. No more 3UK SIM tricks for me (except for Flixster, strangely). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Amazon has just announced their own App Store for Android. Just what the world needs, another stripped down Android app store with fewer apps than the built-in one. Sure sure, if you bought an Archos tablet or slightly dodgy no-name (Sonly Ericcsun maybe) Chinese phone, you won&amp;rsquo;t have the official market but 2 minutes Googling for a workaround usually sorts that out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;But, ever the inquisitive, I downloaded and installed it. The offer of a free &amp;ldquo;Paid App&amp;rdquo; a day was a nice carrot. Of course I had to try the Angry Birds Rio App.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;And then I got that message. That goddammed message we all thought we&amp;rsquo;d seen the back of. Not available in your goddammed region cos you&amp;rsquo;re too goddammed small a country but we&amp;rsquo;ll put our goddammed datacenters here because of the nice tax breaks, thanks very much.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class=&#39;p_embed p_image_embed&#39;&gt;
&lt;img alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; height=&#34;800&#34; src=&#34;http://getfile4.posterous.com/getfile/files.posterous.com/temp-2011-03-22/IDGxFGwHnEbDquvvIIpGAJqsiAaJzfGHvatHgDlIDiwcumtqemJcdyhvIqwc/ScreenShot.png.scaled500.png&#34; width=&#34;480&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Blah blah, country specific licensing, blah blah, copyright issues, blah blah blah. I wonder was that message actually delivered from a server sitting in Dublin? The ultimate insult.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Ye know Amazon, we&amp;rsquo;re already dealing with this bullshit on your Android MP3 Store and on your Kindle Store, so you can take your Android App Store and stick it where the sun don&amp;rsquo;t shine. If Google can figure it out with their legendary ability to negotiate with content providers (&lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt;), surely you can.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;If anyone is looking for Apps outside of the official Market, try &lt;a href=&#34;http://appslib.com/&#34;&gt;Appslib&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.getjar.com/&#34;&gt;GetJar&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;instead.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>