<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ive-Never-Met-An-Engineer-Who-Could-Turn-Their-Hand-To-Businesses on Cross Dominant</title>
    <link>http://conoroneill.net/ive-never-met-an-engineer-who-could-turn-their-hand-to-business.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ive-Never-Met-An-Engineer-Who-Could-Turn-Their-Hand-To-Businesses on Cross Dominant</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:39:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://conoroneill.net/ive-never-met-an-engineer-who-could-turn-their-hand-to-business.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve never met an Engineer who could turn their hand to business</title>
      <link>http://conoroneill.net/ive-never-met-an-engineer-who-could-turn-their-hand-to-business/ive-never-met-an-engineer-who-could-turn-their-hand-to-business.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 09:39:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://conoroneill.net/ive-never-met-an-engineer-who-could-turn-their-hand-to-business/ive-never-met-an-engineer-who-could-turn-their-hand-to-business.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;#&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve never met an Engineer who could turn their hand to business&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With that one line by Alan Sugar on last night&amp;rsquo;s UK Apprentice, I finally realised why Amstrad was never able to grow beyond the odd burst of short term opportunism into a global company. I&amp;rsquo;d like to run a few numbers past Lord Sugar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Amstrad Music Devices sold last year: 0&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number of Apple Music Devices sold last year: 84m&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market share of phones with e-m@ailer technology: 0%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market share of phones with ARM technology: 98% globally&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dell market cap: $30.18B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Viglen valuation: &amp;pound;9.99?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amstrad sale price: &amp;pound;127m&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scientific Atlanta Sale Price: $6.9B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The one difference between those companies and Amstrad? Great business people with a global vision working with great engineers with business sense.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;So Lord Sugar, the next time an engineer runs a business or product idea past you, maybe stop thinking about how you can bundle a tape-recorder with it, and listen to her.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if the BBC dropped property developer Alan from the Apprentice and replaced him with&amp;nbsp;Herman Hauser&amp;nbsp;who, with the creation of the BBC Micro, is ultimately responsible for what became ARM, a technology that is in nearly every mobile phone on the planet? That&amp;rsquo;s someone I would like my kids to aspire to emulating.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Herman, by the way, is a Fellow of The Royal Academy of Engineering.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>